This guy is the best scalper in the
world for the first time ever where he
showcases the power of his strategy and
breaks it down step by step. Freemon.
You wait for this candle. You put the
stop loss here. You target either. This
is the main reason why a lot of traders
use money. They try to anticipate what
the market is doing before the market
does it. People call this manipulation.
They try to break out and they fail.
This is the reason we will get here. You
finally will see a trader break down
candle by candle exactly what he thinks
is going to happen live during New York
session.
>> We are getting ready for the squeeze.
The squeeze will be present here. Look,
>> there you have it.
>> When I told you I will scale out, it's
exactly because when you see this, the
next step is aggressive sellers.
>> Yeah,
>> you you coded the algorithm. This is a
top 1% trader showcasing his strategy
for free
>> to give to the audience a little bit of
reference. You can either do 15 minutes,
3 minutes, you can do 1 hour 5 minutes
or you can do the most aggressive one.
That is what I do. The setup that we
took before is exactly what I will
execute in the world trading cup. How I
did this performance in the world
trading cup is building profit for the
day, building profit for the day,
building profit for the day. And in
directional days, I risk for example,
>> Fabio Valentino. You've never seen
anything like it. It will blow you away.
Make sure you tune in to this episode of
Chart Fanatics. Welcome everyone back to
Chart Fanatics, the go-to channel for
all of the very best trading strategies
and concept breakdowns with the very
best traders in the world. Talking of
which, today we have a worldclass
scalper with us, a future scalper at
that. He has been in the top three in
the world rankings of the Robins Club,
actually achieving in a 12-month period
over 500% return. And that is in the
futures division as well. You probably
already know who it is. If you don't
know, you're going to get to know. We're
going to go through his exact strategy
that he used to be able to achieve those
incredible results on the world stage.
is the one and only Fabia Valentina.
>> Thank you for asking me Ritz. And uh
today we will go deep dive in the model
that I used in the world champion. I
made some videos about it but I keep the
source for this this podcast and um
before starting to explain how the model
works we need to explain what's the
misconception about market structure in
the market. So I will just start drawing
it and explain what 90% of traders do
and why 90% of traders lose money. So
let's start with
>> I think that'll be helpful.
>> The concept of the market structure
that's what usually a lot of traders do
and you can confirm it. This is what
usually it's done uh watching a market
structure shift or change of character
or breakout. There are 100 terms that
you can use for it.
>> And uh what they try to do is they try
to go trend following when pattern like
this presents and then they can just
wait for the uh retracement to jump in
just going through considering we are in
a short sentiment here like using the
concept of supply or order block if you
want to be more fancy following the algo
uh mitigation level and continue to go
down. Now what I tested in a lot of
years of experience is that this pattern
usually doesn't work if you don't frame
it in the correct uh concept and to
frame it in the correct concept you need
to start using
something that is necessary that is the
profile. So you need to understand
exactly where you are in the market and
what's the big picture that you are
watching because if this pattern is
presented when
the bell curve of the distribution of
the day is like this you are exactly
jumping
on a trend to go against
the lower distribution of the volume. M
>> and what this says statistically is that
only 30%
will go through the rest will remain in
what it's called the fair value area. So
you will just keep getting stopped out
till the market really uh decide to take
off. And this is the reason a lot of
traders that try to embark on a journey
of using trend following strategies they
understand really soon that uh the win
rate is not what they were expecting
like 70 80%. when they try to target for
example this level from here and they
say okay I will just have 50% 60% we
rate 1 to three
>> this is not real because you are not you
are not reading what the market is
saying you are trying to predict the
market
>> okay
>> now the good point about order flow and
about volume analysis in general is that
you get the knowledge to understand when
to stay away because if the same pattern
is presented
in this area it's a completely different
situation to explain you this we need to
go to AMT AMT is uh the real nature of
the market and is the concept of auction
market theory market is an auction and
it goes from balanced area where
>> all market participants are
transactioning efficiently to imbalance
Now market is not usually in in
imbalance. It's usually in balance. So
that's the reason why traders that start
take you streak of stop-loss because
they try to get the long and they get
liquidated by you can call what you
want. You can call spring, you can call
liquidation, you can call uh liquidity
seeking everything you want even if it's
not what happens behind the curtains but
you try to get the last spring. M
>> before the move up and you notice that
this 1 to 10 becomes a 1 to2 because you
take four stop to try to do it. Yeah.
Now if you do this simple change and you
wait for the market to get to a
condition of out of balance your win
rate will
>> jump up by at least 20 to 30%. And this
is exactly the building point of the
model that I use. Why I call it a model
and not a strategy? Because the concept
of strategy is a group of rules that you
need to follow strictly. And how can you
follow a group of rules strictly without
understanding the narrative if the
market is a dynamic entity? It's like
trying to cage an animal that is not
made to be in a cage. And it change
every day. It adapts. For example,
yesterday there was this situation about
America bombing Iran. we open with a gap
down really heavy. You cannot expect
that the market today will behave as
Friday. You will have a different
behavior. Now what it's helping you is
understanding how you can use the
profile to exactly time your entry and
your area. So this is the step one of
the model
and is understanding the location. The
location is when you can efficiently
trade when you are out of balance. So
your model is
okay to be traded. You start to see what
all the traders are using. So you start
to see the market structure and you
start to validate which area can be used
to jump on trade.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So now it comes handy to use
supply and demand zones and it comes
handy to understand inefficiency.
Now inefficiency if we can talk about it
uh is misconcepted. nowadays because it
used the term fair value gap.
>> Yeah.
>> But what happened really behind the
curtains in uh the concept of
inefficiency is when one part is more
aggressive than the other.
>> So the market gets really momentum in
one direction and this is if you think
about it is the best moment to transact
because the market is telling you this
and this is not
>> my personal opinion or your personal
opinion. What the market is telling us
look I'm out of balance. Mhm.
>> I'm searching for a new level of balance
that will be down. So it it can be here,
it can be here, it can be here, but I'm
telling you that I will go there. Okay.
>> At the same time is telling you that the
sellers are more aggressive than buyers
because you are getting this kind of
concept. And that's when you go to step
two. Step two is the concept of
validating
the level.
>> Mhm. Because now you have the direction,
you have the condition of the market,
the market status and you have three
possible takeprofit that you can frame
by watching at the other area. Now it
comes handy a concept called
order flow that is not a concept but
it's like an alphabet a new way of
reading the market.
>> So 90% of the trader try to understand
what is happening inside a candle using
multi-time frame analysis. Yeah,
>> I think the real inefficiency is the way
trader analyze the market
>> because it's like trying to get
>> the bullseye
>> Mhm.
>> blinded.
>> Like maybe one time it will work, two
times it will work, but you don't have
exact data about the location. Yeah.
>> So what you can do is that you can use
this area that create the breakouts and
let's consider that I make an arrow here
and we zoom out. what is happening
exactly inside here. Okay. So if this is
the swing point that break this low
traders will just watch for what is
called fair value gap or inefficiency
that is when the candle is not
transaction efficiently. What you can do
is that you can use from point A to
point B
using profile
>> to watch exactly when there are low
volume node.
>> Yes. And I know this because I saw the
other interview that you have made and I
really like the model also of Carmen
Rosato. I think he's a really good order
flow trader and is doing something
really similar to what am I doing
because low volume node it's a really
good reaction level.
>> So you can use it as a continuation. If
we have a low volume node here the
probability that we will go down is
really high.
>> Yeah.
>> So you start to add the concept of
refinement.
>> Mhm. You have the direction, you have
the location, you have the refinement of
the location. Now you need the step
three.
The step three is a little bit more
difficult because it's the part where
you really need the experience and you
cannot just automate it and say okay
when it's happening because it's really
sensitive to market. What I use is
analyzing big orders. So when there is
in one specific point let's say here a
lot of aggression.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. And in order flow platform
typically you see bubbles.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. If you use any platform you can
see bubbles.
>> When there is direction location and
aggression
your ability to predict is zero but your
ability to read is 100. You are exactly
tuning in in the market at the correct
moment and you are not predicting what
is going to do. You are waiting. So this
is really beneficial because when you
see aggression you don't have a huge
stop loss for example out of balance.
You don't have a huge stop loss above
the high but you can get protected
exactly above the big sell aggression.
>> Yeah. So your risk-to-reward rate it's
really big but at the same time the
probability of your trades is really
really big also this one what you are
doing if we can make an example is just
swimming on the direction of the flow.
>> Yeah
>> because you are being pulled down by the
market aggression and also by all the
traders that were long and when this
area breaks will close their position.
So you get the catalyst down, you get
the location of the aggression of the
cell and you get also the target point
that can be based. We will see this on
chart directly on the previous balance
area. Yeah, because how the market
moves.
Let's remove this part here. But how the
market moves is that is seeking
balance. Mhm.
>> So if you go out of here and the
previous balance area was this one where
your P point of control,
>> the previous point where the majority of
the volume was located, it's here. The
probability that when you go this
pattern and you enter here, let's say,
you don't need to break your mind to
understand where you can put your
target. Maybe I can try 1 to 30. And
this is another error. Traders think
that
the risk to reward is not influencing we
rate.
>> The more you seek to go above the AT
daily, the more the probability will get
lower. Hey guys, I hope you're enjoying
this episode so far. And don't forget,
we send every single strategy breakdown
from every episode for free on
chartanatics.com. So the link for that
is in the description below. So just
make sure you click that. You just put
your email in and every single week we
will send you an up-to-date PDF strategy
breakdown for you to keep, to learn
from, to reference for free. And don't
forget, we're also launching Chart
Fanatics Live where your favorite
traders from Chart Fanatics will be live
trading every single day. I will also be
including special guests on the live
Chart fanatics edition. So, make sure
you go subscribe to that YouTube channel
right now. is linked on the main profile
of Chart Fanatics. So, make sure you're
ready for that. Up to 6 million in
futures funding. That's only possible at
one place, Apex Trader Funding. You can
get up to 20 accounts at Apex. No other
futures firm offers anything even close.
And that is why Apex pays out the most
out of any futures firm. Already have
paid out over half a billion dollars.
Half a billion dollars so far to traders
just like you. across the world. They're
no stranger to the podcast or chart
fanatics. We've had some of the record
holders of largest payouts in prop firm
history. Obviously, only through Apex
with Trader Kane, who did over $1.9
million in a single payout, and Jadecap,
who's also done over $2.3 million in a
single payout at Apex. Not only can you
get up to 20 accounts, but also it's
only a one-phase evaluation. There's no
daily draw down. Up to $25,000
of each payout is 100% yours to keep and
90% profit split thereafter. And most of
all, there's no profit cap. Now, don't
forget, you can get a payout at Apex
every 8 days. So, you can get either
their 25K account all the way up to
their 300K account and you can get up to
20 accounts. Now, make sure when you're
getting an account at Apex, you use the
code CF for up to 90% off at Apex Trader
Funding. The link is in the description
below. Use the code CF. Get up to 6
million in futures funding today. Now,
let's get back to the episode. So, with
this model, it's really uncommon that
the market will snap back inside because
when you see aggression and out of
balance, the market needs to search for
new balance.
>> It's like human being. When we are in a
condition of fear, our heart continue to
have takia till we don't get back to
calm. Yeah.
>> And we say okay now we are stable. Okay.
>> This is exactly what the market is
doing. So the step three is getting a
location for aggression. So that the
trigger of the uh model is aggression
and that target point. The target point
also is really objective and I noticed
during this year and also scalping
during the um world cup champion that we
can also get a window during the day
where this model works really good.
Yeah. Okay. So the best session to use
this model it's 100% New York session
specifically for equities. So for NASDAQ
and uh for uh yes and uh is not working
properly during the first hour of London
session. I try to use this model and
during London session
>> you see out of balance back inside
balance out of balance back inside
balance. This is called by traders fake
outs. Yeah. And it's usually when the
market is not
>> um really clear about direction. So um
one
concept that I use to remove this is
that I don't trade before New York
session. I only trade before New York
session in the world cup but with a mean
reverting model.
>> Okay. So I was doing the opposite and we
can go also through it because it's
extremely profitable and it's even
easier to implement this one and the
following one.
So let's say that in a balanced market
from the statistical perspective during
the London session usually in indices
you have mean reverting behavior. Okay.
So it's less common that you will see a
trend.
>> Yeah. You will see bouncing and going
out. So one other model that I uh am
using is the one that takes opportunity
of when the market is deep discount
based on the volume distribution and
misnaps back in. Now it's the same
concept. It's the opposite. Now we are
seeking for buy. We have a target. Why
we are using this target? Because this
target is where the maximum volume
volume is transacted. So there is
interest like market operators are
willing to transact here.
>> Mhm.
>> What I do in this area is that I don't
take the first movement. I wait I wait
for the first breakout. You can use
price action for this because I get
clear market participants of what they
want to do. I don't risk that this is
only a retracement and then they
collapse.
>> Exactly. Yeah, I get a movement that is
clear when I get the first breakout and
I'm back inside the balance.
This probability is really high.
>> Mhm.
>> This really high probability. Now to
increase even more the probability, I
wait for the hand of the big market
participants. So I wait for big trades.
>> Yeah.
>> So the common bubble of buy order that I
can just say, okay, I jump in with them.
>> I don't need to be a wizard. I jump in
when the best one are jumping in with
big volume
>> and if I'm wrong, I want to be wrong
immediately.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> Because
>> all the additional losing that you get
when you are inexperienced trader and
say maybe I put the stop loss larger
when the market is going against you
because I will it will snap back. This
is really something that will destroy
your bank account and your trading
account. What you need to do is be wrong
immediately and when you are right when
you see that you get an additional
breakout immediately stop to break even.
>> Yeah.
>> So after this small movement you are
already risk free on
>> you quite aggressive with your risk
management.
>> I'm aggressive with my risk management
because I need to put in this small
amount of ticks.
>> Mhm.
>> 0.25% of my account or 0.5% on the
account. So you say you could do this or
take this concept without order flow for
example
>> but of course the order flow just allows
you to have more confirmation align more
with the larger orders.
>> It's working also for price action
>> but it's like something that when you
see it you cannot unsee it.
>> So um when you are trading your mind as
an orderflow trader says okay price
action is nice but let's see what is
happening in the level. you want to see
it and then I think it's not convenient
nowadays to not use orderflow for one
simple reason we are edge and edge
seekers as traders
>> every 5% more win rate brings us more
money at the end of the month every one
hour two hour three hour more at the end
of the month is more money for us so why
not using all the information available
I've been in trading floor I seen how
they trade and institutional trader
considering that 90% is algo trading
nowadays. But the discretionary trading
for alternative markets, they still use
orderflow. They use orderflow because
they want to see what they are doing.
Maybe they are more long-term because
they work with huge amount of capital.
So they prefer to use volume profile.
But for short term, after 10 years of
trading, I never seen something better
than order flow. So still nowadays the
model is not getting changed. The only
change that I've made is uh during high
compression period that we have seen in
2023 and 24
>> the the month that you are going through
summer like end of March. Yeah. May June
you see the market is getting a little
bit compressed and August like NASDAQ
movement are really choppy. So um what
you can do is just say to create
specific condition where you will not
transact. So this model it's okay for
London session, it's not okay for New
York session,
>> but it's perfect for the summer. So I'm
giving you a model that it's perfect for
the months that we are going in because
this is the behavior maybe with Iran and
America and Israel, it will not be the
summer
>> to do this model. But um but yes it's
working uh properly.
>> But to your point in terms of orderflow
wise regardless of
>> you know conditions that understanding
of order flow remains right. So in terms
of the principles that you're using when
using orderflow and understanding that
information and deciphering that
information regardless of the conditions
whether we're compressed or whether
we're getting a lot of volatility and
movement
>> the the lessons and principles you take
from order flow remains universal. So
outside of because with price action and
purely price action, the problem is one,
you're guessing, right? You're trying to
guess where stops are. You're trying to
guess where the big players are because
you can't see it.
>> But equally, when conditions change, the
same concepts aren't universal. Now you
have to change and and be able to adapt.
While with the order flow, you still
have to adapt. you know, you still have
to change in terms of your maybe your
risk management, your trade management,
but the order flow itself, like those
orders are still orders, those stop
losses, those those uh participants are
still going to be the same.
>> Um, but just a quick question for
yourself. You weren't were you always an
orderflow trader or is it something you
picked up?
>> No, I was a free action trader, but I'm
really open-minded. So if someone comes
to me and say, "Fabio, you can improve
your risk-to-reward from here to here
using option flow."
>> Yeah,
>> I'm really open to it. Like I think that
a trader needs to be the most
open-minded person because if a new
tools for example, if new data like MBO
orders can improve your model, you
shouldn't be you shouldn't put your ego
here and say no, my model is the best
one. if it's improving your profit
factor and sharp ratio just use it and
connecting to your point I went to order
flow also also because the price action
it's harder to replicate for students
>> because let's say that we have 100
people watching this okay and we say
okay use a break of structure in favor
of the trend for someone a break of
structure is this for someone can be
external breakoff structure for someone
they take the big swing and is this the
breakoff structure? Okay, if I say to
you look
drop for the full day the profile the
profile is this one. This is the level
where you are out of balance is not it
cannot be this it cannot be this it
cannot be this. If I say to you it's
when you go here just put a filter of 30
contracts on NASDAQ on the one minute
you cannot think it's here because you
will see the ball. So it's really
objective. Now there is a skill in
reading of course market sentiment,
market change. But when I explain you
something, it's something that you can
go home test it and you will see exactly
what I'm seeing with price action. I
think the the subjective analysis is
really heavy especially if you start
doing puts multi-time frame. So
>> definitely yeah
>> from daily to H4 to H1 to 15 minutes, 3
minutes, 1 minutes. What's the
probability that the trade that you
frame is the same that the trade that
your student will frame? It's really
low.
>> That's what I was going to say. So when
it comes to say teaching for example
when there is no orderflow that
subjectiveness becomes quite a
difficulty because everyone has a
different perception
>> as you said as you you know there's a
really good example of of showing that.
But then when you have order flow
>> regardless of that the time frame
potentially and you know where you're
looking that the areas on the charts are
all going to be the same. Everyone's
going to see the same thing. And those
numbers are going to be reflected
exactly the same across the board to
every single person. While you know even
the subjectiveness of say just
candlesticks like a large red candle to
one person might just another candle
while to another person they'll be like
oh my goodness the market is completely
falling off a cliff
>> when they explain the model when you see
a big candle how much it's a big candle
how much ATR you you include. So there
is a lot of subjectivity and also let's
consider that
we have three level of analysis. We have
lagging,
we have real time and we are leading.
Lagging are indicators. So if you get
MACD, if you get stochastic, if you get
RSI,
this is created as
uh derivative of price.
>> So you get uh MACD that is always going
after price, never anticipating.
>> Yeah,
>> price is real time. So you are watching
>> what is happening as an effect in real
time. But with volume, you are watching
the narrative before the price created.
I give you an example of something that
I never explained. Okay? And this is
something that really helped me to see
the develop the developing pressure to
be able to put at break even sooner than
other people. Okay? So let's say that we
are here. We have a long bias. We are
out of balance and we have the previous
day point of control. Okay. So with
price action when can we put that break
even? When we break this level. Yeah.
You agree with me? Yes. Because we have
level of protection that we can put here
and we say okay it will retest and go.
>> Yeah. We shouldn't break that low.
Right.
>> Volume we can use one tool that is
called CVD. That is cumulative volume
delta. What cumulative volume delta is
giving you is a benchmark for pressure
of volume.
>> Mhm.
>> So you are out of balance. So the
probability you will find a new point of
balance is high with cumulative volume
delta. You see this is the price maybe
you see the cumulative volume delta
doing this when you are here the
cumulative volume delta is doing this.
What does it mean that aggressive buyers
are really pushing on the gas and there
is a lot of interest because as the
price goes up you don't see sellers
aggressive but you see that buyers are
willing to buy at higher price and if we
are at an auction and there is a a
limited piece of Mustang from 1969 okay
>> and the base auction is 1 million and
you see buyers starting 1.2 1.4 1.6 six
it means that the price
is probably going up because they are
interested in the piece.
>> So what you can do when you see that
cumulative volume delta is pushing up
and you see this leg already building
you can already put to break even. Yeah
>> because you know that as the smallest
retracement aggressive buyers will
continue to push up and you are
protected.
>> Yeah.
>> This is something that you can do with
only with leading indicators you cannot
do before. Of course, I didn't talk
about global macro, but also global
macro, it's a leading indicator or
onchain analysis for crypto, but for
intraday scalping, like orderflow is the
benchmark tool. Let's take a break for a
minute there, guys, cuz I want to tell
you about the best CFD prop firm in the
entire industry, Funded Next. Funded
Next is a proud sponsor of Chart
Fanatics, and they have been leading the
CFD prop firm industry for many years.
Literally a top three prop firm. Now,
why is that? Let me quickly just run
through all the incredible things that
they do. First off, they have challenges
for every trader. Whatever you're
looking for, they have. They have a
one-step challenge. They have two-step
challenges. And now industry-leading
instant funding. You get on demand
payouts. You get instant access to
funding. You get a no daily loss limit.
And for every 10% you make on the
account, it doubles your account size.
Mind-blowing. Absolutely crazy. Now let
me tell you though the trading
conditions they are the best in the
market when it comes to raw spreads and
there are no slippage. When it comes to
trading platforms they have MetaTrader
4, MetaTrader 5 and C trader as well.
Something unique to Funded Next is that
on every challenge type you can get once
you've achieved 10% on your funded
account up to 15% of the profits during
the challenge phase given back to you.
In addition to that, you can also get a
reward bonus equivalent to the same
amount as your subscription fee on your
first payout. And just in case that's
not enough, there's no time limit on
most challenges. News trading is
allowed. There's no imposed limits on
instruments or position sizes. They have
scaleup plans that can 10x your account
size. And something that they did first,
if you don't receive your payout within
24 hours, you will receive an additional
$1,000
compensation. Now, if that doesn't tell
you that they're for traders, I don't
know what will. Now, make sure you use
the code CF to get the best offer
available at Funded Next right now. The
link is in the description below. Make
sure you join Funded Next today. Now,
let's get back to the episode. I love
that example to be fair because if you
really think about an auction that's
probably the closest that the everyday
person might have some sort of insight
into or at least know and understand how
they operate uh as a as a usual auction.
So in this case the car or house for
example um you'll see the same thing if
let's say even when there are buyers who
want to buy but let's say if the auction
price is starting too high
>> they don't they don't really like where
it's starting at you'll see actually the
auction begins anyone at a million no
one answers no one says anything so then
the auctioneer or whoever's like running
the auction will bring the price down
until there's some interest and then you
never know like it might seem like oh no
one wants this car no one wants this uh
vehicle or in this case obviously no one
wants to participate or place any orders
in this market.
>> But then once it hits the level that
people are interested at, let's say if
it's that car example again, let's say
we started at a million but no one's
interested. Bring it down to 800,000.
Now suddenly someone's interested, one
person's interested. Okay, we bid it up,
but now people who were there for that
particular vehicle moment.
>> Yes. And then you'll suddenly see how
Yeah, we started at a million and no one
was interested, but suddenly we're
blasting up to 1.25 25 million and
there's still orders and still more bids
and therefore that velocity and that
amount of demand
>> at the moment
>> you go to the market price because if
the market price is 2.1 million you
start to see at 1.9 million of auction
market participants saying okay let's go
on increment of 50,000 not 200,000 so
the market gets lower and you build new
balance
>> and then the point of control is the
seller that close it usually the auction
So um this is how really the market
works and this is what I use daily to
frame my entry and um then what's good
about orderflow is that it's really um
you can adapt it to every market
condition. For example, if you have a
model with price action that is working
really good, you don't need to abandon
your model. just see if you can get
better precision and remove the losing
trades using this concept.
>> Mhm.
>> So it's not something that you will not
start from scratch. Yeah. Just
>> expand the level of knowledge you have
from candlestick charts.
>> So like you said earlier as a trader and
and a pure trader at that and who's
someone who's focused on trading 100%.
>> That's your goal is to how do you build
more edge? How do you squeeze more edge
out of the same knowledge? playbook or
strategy that you're using because
that's really what you do at that point.
You're not jumping, okay, I've got this
strategy, but I want to find a better
one. That's not how the mindset is,
right? And then if you come across a
really good playbook and edge and
strategy, you always can start to add
that. But your focus point is how do I
make this playbook the best it can be?
How can I be the best trader possible?
And in this case, you might have a
profitable price action model,
>> but your goal then is okay, how do I
squeeze more out of it,
>> right? So in terms of using orderflow if
you're not using that already that would
definitely help you to squeeze more out
of it. Now not I'm sure there might be
some people who try and learn orderflow
and go n this is a bit more complex for
me and uh therefore you know for that
particular individual it might not be as
helpful for example
>> but I would say it's probably a slimmer
amount of people right
>> um
>> but the worst thing you can do is just
not even try because you're already
writing it's like people who need to
learn fundamentals right and macro
>> they don't because they it's complex and
you know the price action's enough
>> much to study
>> yeah but in reality when you look at
even just this year but co was a great
example of it for as a lot of traders
came into the markets but even just this
year for example was a great example
last year yes we had quite a bull market
but there wasn't really a crazy amount
of fundamentals behind um you know in
terms of like changes and volatility
changes and market changes while this
year we're we're just coming into
towards the end of June and literally
we've seen highs lows we've seen the
markets completely shift month after
month after week and it's probably not
going to change and we call this a Trump
But but um again if you don't know macro
it's so easy for you to sit there and go
the markets are crazy I can't understand
what's going on versus the people who do
have an understanding and it I won't
even class it as like a deep deep deep
understanding some people you just have
a basic knowledge
>> allows them to have more clarity and
calmness which as a trader as we know is
extremely important u one thing we'll do
so from here where should we go from
here should we should we uh recap the
two models quickly did we we covered two
right
>> two to go one point before that is edge
decay.
>> Yeah, let's do it. Yeah.
>> Before going to to recap the model,
>> let's do it.
>> Um the concept of edge decay is when
your model lose edge.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. And this is something I notice a
lot with price action. So for example,
before I was using supply and demand in
trend following and when the volatility
change for example you are creating one
rule that you have moving average long
and we are adding to the trend when you
get here. Okay. uh volatility change. So
the the length of the swing if it goes
from here to here you already take a lot
of stop loss not because you are wrong
the direction is right but the market
will just swing higher and I think every
discretionary trader notice it. Yeah.
>> So this is edge decay and it's your lose
of edge in the change of market
condition. What's also Jim Simmons was
talking about with his renaissance fund
and um with or the flow what it's
interesting is that you cannot actually
have an edge decay because what you are
watching is the true nature of the
market.
>> So you are not framing the market in
something that is close rule from A to B
but you are understanding what's
happening. And I will give you an
example of something that improved my
model by four or five point
in we rate that it's a lot if you are a
scalper and is the following one before
>> if you are like closed in a range but
you are trading price action and you are
trading continuation with brick test
model is really common. Okay. So you
wait for this then you wait for the week
down and on the
>> on on the test you go long.
>> Yeah. When if you start to do one simple
exercise and you start to only use order
flow to zoom out when this is happening
like you you take one specific part. So
you cannot say that order flow is
complex. You take the same candle just
you make an exercise watch cumulative
volume delta here and orders.
You can use also footprint for this. If
you see that at this level there is a
lot of a aggression and the cumulative
volume delta is doing here this it means
that this movement is not supported and
the probability that you will go down
it's here and is something that is
telling you before the price bring you
to stop. So you can just decide not to
jump in. And this is a comp a concept
that I want to cover because it's
something that I went through when uh
the price action model was not working
properly during the um 2019 and I had to
step up the game and I was thinking no
no I need to study from zero and I need
to implement something that will cancel
and raise all the learning curve that I
got with price action. But it's not like
this just you will start from where you
are before. Yeah,
>> just understanding what's happening
behind the market.
>> Of course, it's easier to think that the
market is dominated by some black entity
behind the table because understanding
the mechanic is difficult. But I can
guarantee you that you will improve as a
trader.
>> Mhm.
>> And uh so we go now on the summary of
the two models.
>> Yeah.
>> And we start with the trend model.
So this model is a trend following model
and we will go before on the timing
that is New York session. Okay. So we
want the biggest amount of volatility to
implement this model in live market
condition and uh I don't advise to keep
the trades for the night. So this is a
model that gets close as soon as the
market close. You don't bring overnight
trades because you also need more margin
for futures. It's not convenient at all.
Just if you are in profit or if you are
in loss, cut the position and tomorrow
it's another day for this one. So this
is the timing. Then when we go on the
step one, the first step is
understanding market state.
We can only have two market state. We
can have a balanced market
price action going here and we can have
an imbalance market.
Okay, with this model we want to
transact
here. We are not interested in this
market condition. So also for the
gamblers
uh you have one rule that keeps you out
of the market and this is really
important because when I start scalping
with price action every movement was
okay for me like every small impulse and
then you say okay I took three stop for
the day I'm out and then the big moves
arrives. So this is the lock where you
cannot enter if you don't have exactly
what the market needs to tell you. Yeah,
>> this is the market state and what we
frame as the step one. Then we need the
location.
The location is exactly
your swing point. That is this one.
Okay.
>> Mhm. that you need to analyze deeply
because you need to understand if you
want to jump in here, if you want to
jump in here or just if you want to jump
on the train sometimes from the lowest
point because momentum is so high that
you can just say okay I jump here
>> but I cover myself here. So it's still a
good riskto-reward rate.
>> What you use to do this you you use
profile.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Use profile and what you search is
low volume node. Mhm.
>> So where the mark let's make try to draw
the profile. Okay. Say that this is the
profile for the swing point.
What we can see here is that this is the
low volume node. Not the best drawing.
But
>> I think it's understandable that
>> we're going to see on the charts, right?
>> The
>> the point where the lowest volume get
transacted.
>> What you can do here is
do this. Okay.
So what I do usually is I don't put a
limit order.
>> Okay?
>> I put an alert a little bit below.
>> Because when it arrives there,
>> I want to see big trades, big orders.
Okay? So as we were seeing before, we
started from the timing, we went through
the market state, we went through the
location, go to the step three, that is
execution or trigger. What you want to
see is aggression. If you are seller,
you want a big red ball. Okay? When you
see a big red ball, you can jump in and
your stop loss will go here and your
target will be the previous balance
area. Yeah. So, if we are here, the
previous balance area, it's here. Let's
see the P.
This is our target. And we are going to
take out not half the position and let
it run. we are going to take out the
full position because the probability is
that the market will reverse from it 70%
of the time. So we are it's just not
worth to keep the position for only 30%
probability more.
>> Yeah,
>> better that we take all that we can in
this case.
>> Now let's go to the model two and the
model two is
mean reverting.
So the model 2 is using the market state
that is the opposite. Yeah. So he's
using consolidation.
Market state is consolidation and is
when the profile
>> is protecting
from breaking here and breaking here.
Okay. So you get from here to here to
here to here. What we are trying to take
is the out of balance condition that get
back inside balance. And as I told you,
we are not trying to take the first
swing because it's risky. Yeah,
>> we are getting the second swing. So when
we have the first breakout,
>> we are just waiting for the retracement.
It's the same concept as before. Now the
location is this wing.
>> Yeah.
>> You frame the location, you wait for the
retracement.
>> Mhm.
>> So let's consider that this is this
wing. Same stuff low volume node
aggression seller consider that we are
here maybe where we go we don't go here
this is an error that everyone is doing
the probability is not high you go here
you go to the
>> where the bulk of the auctions taking
place
>> where the probability that you will go
to balance it's really high
>> and if you are wrong you want to be
wrong immediately if you have big sell
orders here immediately Here it's your
stop loss. A small trick for the
scalpers, aggressive scalpers. There is
a way to avoid slippage or at least
minimize slippage put the stop loss not
above the high.
>> Yeah.
>> Because above the high there are a lot
of orders and what you see is that
market will accelerate. Example when you
you take previous daily high, previous
daily low, previous weekly high,
previous daily low. You see that the
market even if it's a failu now it's
going down it accelerate. So you lose an
additional amount of tick that you can
protect. How you can protect them just
put your stop loss one or two ticks
below the high.
>> Okay.
>> So you are taken out before everyone
that is before acceleration takes place.
>> And it's worth it. I tested it and it's
worth it because sometimes you get five
ticks, six tick of and it's a lot
>> because the overall chances of price
getting to one or two ticks below that
high and then not go for
>> not it's almost zero. No, it's not zero.
Sometimes it happens and you just want
to cut your ends but on the long term
like statistically wise it's worth it.
Yeah,
>> cuz in this case for example, just to
recap, so this recap wise, timing wise,
you're looking at potentially London,
>> right? And then in your consolidation
periods such as normally your summer
months, right? Yes. um just as an
example. But in terms of the recapping
the thesis, it's the fact that yes, you
know, we're in a range and yes, you
could target here because price has
shown that yes, we're going from high
down to low, but the highest probability
is that auction auction area where the
bulk of the orders and transactions are
taking place versus, okay, yes, we could
get here, but there are chances that we
could get to there and rebound back up
to that auction area again or rebound
back up to the high that there's there's
too many variables trying to target here
or especially lower versus the highest
probable and that you know it's not
guaranteed, nothing's guaranteed, but
the chances are way more in your favor,
especially considering the information
you're taking on board. Uh because
again, you're not just entering from the
first spike out of the range. You're
going to wait for your confirmation and
then look to execute.
>> Exactly. Exactly. And then consider that
there are some days that they are really
blessed days
>> where you have this model.
>> Yeah.
>> Then the market breaks the low. you
activate the second model for New York
and you take two amazing target and you
are done for the week.
>> Um, so yes, these are the the two model.
Now the tricky part is correctly
identifying the consolidation because
you can make it as simple as possible
and say
>> this is one day.
>> Mhm.
>> So I use the profile of the previous
day. Yeah.
>> Okay. So it's easy. You don't need to
have headache about it. You just wait
for the Okay. There is a more advanced
model where you have more execution
where you get the ability to identify
the consolidation phase. Okay, you just
take an orderflow platform and you see
the compressed candles
and you just plot the profile on there.
This is what we were going to do because
it needs a little bit more skill. M
>> I will explain you pull out the profile
and I will show you something really
interesting that not trading view but
some orderflow platform are willing to
give you also the delta of the transact
volume before so you can see for each
level who is dominating the market
>> this is really useful because if you see
here that you are going up and is
dominated by buyers it's not the best
condition to get a buy trades because
the probability that you will do this
it's really high.
>> Yeah.
>> At the same time, if in this area you
see a huge delta cell when you break
out, it's your birthday.
>> Yeah.
>> You just go for it.
>> Mhm. Should we go over the quickly the
pros and cons and then we'll pull out
the charts. Let's take a break for a
minute there, guys, cuz I want to tell
you about our incredible sponsor,
TradeZella. Tradezeller is the number
one trading tool in the entire trading
industry. Tradezella allows you to
become a more profitable trader. Allows
you to make immense progress as a
trader, no matter if you're a beginner
or an advanced level trader, because it
makes journaling easy. It makes
journaling something that is fun and
enjoyable and something that is
interactive. So, no matter if you're a
crypto trader, no matter if you're a
futures trader, no matter if you're a
forex trader, no matter if you're a
stock trader, all you have to do is
select your broker, your platform of
choice, and connect it to Tradesella,
and it will automatically sync your
trades and pull all of that data onto
the dashboard, making journaling and
finding your edge and adapting your edge
so easy. In collaboration with Tradzella
and Chart Fanatic specifically, we are
actually getting the playbooks from the
episodes that we're filming with these
incredible verified traders and adding
them as playbooks onto Trade Zela. So,
you can actually go on there and see the
rule sets already predefined. So, make
sure you check that out as well. Now,
you can actually get 10% off your
monthly subscription using CF10 on
Tradzella right now. But more
importantly, I would say CF20 for 20%
off your yearly subscription with
Tradezella. The links for Tradezella are
in the description below. So, make sure
you go check them out. Use CF20, get 20%
off your yearly subscription, become a
better trader today. Now, let's get back
to the episode.
>> Yes. So, let's go on the pros and cons.
The cons is that if you use the second
model, compression days are killing you
because sometimes
uh especially if you don't work on the
daily profile but you work on the um
short-term profile that you can trace by
yourself.
>> Um consolidation is killing your win
rate because maybe you take five small
stop-loss. Yeah,
>> five small stop losses maybe a lose a
loss on $5,000.
>> Mhm.
>> Then you take one take profit and it's
like 15 20,000 but at the same time
psychologically
the win rate gets lower and if you see a
lot of red in your account even if at
the end of the week you are still
profitable it's heavy for beginners
>> it's heavy. So one uh bad concept is
consolidation that directly affect win
rate for the model and this is the
reason I created a second model because
when I lose with one
>> I make profit with the other one. So
it's like balancing the equity curve
giving you more execution but the draw
down gets lower. So it's worth it. This
is the first cons. The second one is
it's stress. We need to be honest with
it.
>> Yeah. when uh um your trades gets to the
level not in a proper but in a real
account where the single position is
worth the salary that you were taking
for example 10 years ago.
>> So you are risking 2,000 3,000 4,000
5,000 per position and in 2 minutes 3
minutes you can lose it.
>> Mhm.
>> Of course at the end of the month it's
profitable but on the short term it's
heavy on the mindset. Yeah. Specifically
if you go through the moment and there
will be moments where you take streak of
stop- loss
>> like in the world cup I show
transparently transparently the trades I
was taking and one day I received a lot
of insult from the people on the
Instagram because I've been transparent
of one day taking eight stop loss like
small stop loss like five tick 10 ticks
but a lot of stop loss because it was a
day that
>> and you risk sometimes 0.2
>> 0.2 2 0.3. So it's
>> like nice stop loss is 1.8%. 2% is not a
big amount. You can deal with it. But
when you talk to people and you say look
I took nine stop loss. You see learn to
trade.
>> Yeah.
>> So so so they they just think that a
profitable trader is a trader that
having a huge amount of win rate. They
don't consider that maybe the stop loss
are incredibly smaller than gains.
>> Yeah. So the the stress part and the the
third cons is the time commitment.
>> Mhm.
>> Like to execute this model you cannot do
it as an hobby. You cannot do it as a
side hustle. You need to be in on the
screen from the starting of the newer
session to the end because the position
not only need to be executed is set and
don't forget it's set and check is
something like this because you need to
trail your stop you need to manage
>> there's a model for real traders. This
is very
>> this is a model if you want that trading
gets your fulltime income. Yeah. Okay.
Now on the London session I manage three
I manage companies with my business
partner but in the new year session
three or four hours I do this
>> and it's necessary you cannot just get
out you can't just decide that after a
certain time you don't open trades so
you can enjoy dinner that's of course
can be can be something good on the pros
the first one is
number of trades
Why this is good?
>> Because draw down gets covered really
fast if you have a big profit factor and
sharper ratio. So you can take nine stop
loss for the day but by the end of the
week I was again in profit. I was high
watermark. So I was creating new high on
the equity equity curve
>> and uh also a big number of trades
creates something interesting for hedge
funds that wants to give you capital.
Mhm.
>> Because a model that in 12 months does
2,400 execution is more respected than a
long-term model that in 12 months have
30 trades.
>> Yeah.
>> Because the data sample wise this model
is more valuable.
>> Interesting. It's giving you a lot of
room of improvement and is giving you a
lot of data analysis that you can input
>> and you understand really fast if your
model is not working properly in certain
market condition
>> because for example I have a benchmark
that is the maximum amount of stop- loss
I've taken that is 11 stop loss
>> okay
>> it's a humbling experience
>> but you know that the market can stay in
compression for one full week
>> you know that every day it's a fake
breakout for one week. I saw the last
videos of Carmen Rosato. He was like
taking a huge amount of uh stop-loss
like for 3 weeks, but he's still in
profit for the month.
>> Yes.
>> That's the good part about scalper, the
number of execution, and it's really
easy to go back in profit.
>> The second good part about trading with
this model is that
you don't need headache.
Why you don't need headache? because the
prediction part is not there.
>> You are just paid to read what the
market is telling you. So I don't need
to start to say considering the angle of
gun maybe the price will skyrocket to
this price because this no just
>> this is the market state. This is the
location. This is the aggression. This
is this is my trades. Mhm.
>> And another good part, maybe this is the
best part. I should have put this that
you cannot do revenge trading because if
you don't have the condition to trade
when you trade large amount of size, you
just don't feel confident to execute.
>> Mhm.
>> If there are not the condition of
aggression just it's not worth it to to
do it. So the the third part is just
there is no headache in deciding and no
revenge trading in executing something
that is not there.
>> Yeah.
>> You know with projection I don't know if
you ever experience it but sometimes you
see something that is not there just
because you want to trade. So you create
the setup
>> well you can have a bias and then if
let's say one time frame isn't giving
you that bias you can just filter
through until you find one. Like our
time 10 time frames let's say eight of
them are long but you want to be short.
You'll just go to the one that says
sure. Yeah. You know.
>> Yeah. Yeah. This is something that uh I
also did it like our ego is bringing us
to the condition that if we say in our
mind that the bias for the day long as
and the news are long we will just take
every demand here
>> because we think every demand that is
getting break it's a fake
>> and even down here
>> even say it's taking liquidity
>> till this wing doesn't get st out and of
course this is a liquidation. So you
also trade the reverse and then when you
get destroyed you
>> that's normally the last last resort
right
>> last resort. Yes.
>> But another pro is that it's a high risk
it can be a high risk to reward.
>> It can huge risk to reward when uh it's
not common. I need to be honest but when
NASDAQ is pushing is pushing heavy
>> and when you are in from the breakout of
the level and you are because you need
to consider that our target is the P.
Okay. If you are here there is no P
because you are creating value up.
>> True.
>> So you just decide to trail for the day.
>> Trail. Yeah.
>> Okay. Sometimes you get some 1 to 30 1
to 40. It's not common but it can
happen.
>> But even high risk reward like 1 to 4 1
to 5 that's a common reassurance.
>> One to one to 2.5 is the minimum.
>> Yeah.
>> 1 to five is common.
>> 1 to 10 20 is not common. It only when I
do 1 to 10 1 to 20 it means that you see
on the NASDAQ 2% 3% for the day.
>> Yeah.
>> So it means that I really follow the
market properly but I cannot do 1 to 10
if the market is doing 0.25 for the day
0.5 like I'm in tune with it like I I
>> plus it's not like you're focused on
risk-to-reward. It's just part of the
model. You're focused on understanding
what's going on and then reacting and
following your model accordingly.
>> Yeah. When when your model and when your
primary focus gets to protection of
capital and risk management,
>> you increase the profit.
>> Definitely
>> like when you put your focus on
something that you think it's not
directly related is when you make the
most amount of profit.
>> Well, now let's go into well the charts
I guess the actual trade examples. Yeah.
So, as we've established, this is truly
a strategy and playbook for real
traders. traders who really want to not
only trade but understand the markets at
a deep level. So now we're actually
going to go over trade examples on the
charts uh of those same playbooks and uh
what do we have in front of us here?
>> So this is a orderflow platform is a
deep chart and uh what we have here is
volume profile uh distribution profile
of specific consolidation area. So what
I was explaining to you before is that
you can make it stupid simple putting
just daily profile. You can do this also
from trading view. Maybe the volume will
not be as precise as this or you can
just do it um identifying the most
interesting compression area. As you can
see here they are clearly visible where
the market didn't transacted higher or
lower. It just stayed in compression. I
use every day this area. And what I
wanted to show you before is exactly
this. You see here is the volume. Okay,
this is the volume. This is how much
volume is transacted per price level.
This blue line is the value area. So
every time you see the model in
consolidation when it gets back, get
back in target.
>> Get back in target
>> up get back in target
>> down get back in target.
>> This one will be stop loss. But you have
the second model. You have the execution
model of this in this consolidation. We
need also to be honest that you don't
identify it immediately. You need you
can identify maybe from here you can
take these two trades. This one is
really uncommon because you start to see
the real compression. Yeah. It's too
early. Exactly.
>> Now what is interesting is that you can
frame also the delta. What is the delta?
The measure amount of volume getting
transacted from one side on one place
level. the aggression and if you see
here look how much is big the delta is
exactly at the level where they
accumulate the last time and created
this extreme breakout. Okay, this one
here I will also explain you later why
the news catalyst is something where a
lot of people think that the market is
seeking liquidity but at the moment this
movement is make because market maker go
out of the market.
>> So the volatility gets higher because
you have less limit orders and in this
case uh the market explode up to create
a new level of balance. So in this case
we have reversion model, reversion
model, reversion model, reversion model
and stop here probably
>> aggressive model here breakout and we
will go deep dive in the lower time
frame because now we are in 5 minutes
then we will drop down to 1 minute. This
model can be used in every time frame
like to give to the audience a little
bit of reference. You can either do 15
minutes 3 minutes, you can do 1 hour 5
minutes
>> or you can do the most aggressive one.
That is what I do. 5 minutes 1 minute.
>> Okay.
>> So 5 minutes is to watch the breakout
candle. Okay. This one I don't go deep
dive inside it because it's impossible
to execute. You see it went out of
balance. No retracement, low volatility,
low liquidity. So it's impossible to
take. Then we will go to this one that
is the 23 is this morning.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. This morning we will see exactly
how the model play out perfectly on the
trend following side. So I will show you
how also the model behaves in London
session. Even if I only use this in New
York session, the model really works as
also reversion model in London and New
York. Yeah, I want to show you the
entity of the momentum to explain you
why I do New York. This is New York.
This is you see how much is compressed
more retracement. This when you take it,
it just explode. Yeah.
>> And this is what I was trying to explain
you before as the flow getting in tune
with the flow. So what we do now that
our area are clear, we can go to one
minute time frame
and we will start with the first one.
Okay. What we have here is the previous
area. This is the value area high. This
is the value area low. This is the poke.
Okay. So, we are clearly out of balance
from this movement.
>> You can either be aggressive or just say
I want to clear out also the high.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I just want that there is no
obstacles in my explosion higher. This
is something that I usually do. I don't
transact only when you break out. I wait
because it can be the reversion model
here, you know.
>> Then what we do, this is
the magic.
We activate the orders that are getting
filter for the amount of aggression.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So my filter usually is around 20
to 30. Okay. In this case, I think it's
pretty visible. And this is the best
example you can have. Look how much is
balanced. Look what happens when
momentum is building.
>> So what I was saying to you even before
the breakout, if you know how this stuff
works, can you understand that something
is happening here?
>> You are going from small orders balance
to
>> someone buying aggressively and
continuation aggressively. Also look at
the amount of big orders that you have
in bullish momentum and in bearish
momentum. So you can clearly understand
if you are following the flow or not. So
the trades here
is like I was saying before either the
momentum continuation trades that you
get framing the level with a huge
presence of buy aggression and this is
another model that I also show on
YouTube that is just not because this
stuff happens in one minute. Okay. So
every candle is one minute. You can
either be fast and use only big orders
or just as I was saying before plot the
profile from the beginning to the end of
the impulse and say look let's zoom out
in here what we have we have a lack of
volume here.
>> Yeah.
>> So there is a huge area that we can use
as a low volume node.
>> Okay. So when you have the retracement
and you get close to the area, you can
decide to take this as an aggression
>> or
I will take this one as an aggression.
Okay, maybe you enter here, you have the
mitigation of the level and then you
have just continuation. Now the more you
wait to enter, the more it gets risky.
>> Yeah. Because if you enter here, you are
getting to a point where sellers can say
it's too expensive the price. I went out
of balance. But you want to be in fast
and close fast.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> So from here you can just identify from
when the aggression is still bullish.
>> I will start to be a little bit afraid
here. I will start to say look the
market is compressing again. The sellers
are starting to fight back this huge
momentum. Yeah.
>> So maybe I can put my stop loss in
profit.
>> Gotcha.
>> Below this low.
>> Then what happens that the market
against you don't need to be a wizard.
The market give you clues because this
breakout you see it's participated by
huge buyers.
The sellers try to get control back
here. But what the market print a week.
So it means that they cannot control the
movement. And I would completely take
out the position where I see that
because big sellers no follow up small
sellers big sellers huge follow up
>> and close
>> on this candle you can go out you can go
out on stop loss in profit or you can go
out when you reach your risk-to-reward
rates.
>> Okay.
>> Because with this as an example just to
highlight.
>> Yes.
>> So as you say
>> sellers no follow through but
consolidation. Yes,
>> we continue. We break out. We see the
buyers
>> again from the low.
>> Yeah. Wick, but no follow through.
>> Exactly.
>> But could you say that these sellers are
entering, they're maybe not getting
stopped out, they're still in the
market. So then when you finally see the
sellers and then the follow through now,
you know, you you use this buildup of
sellers previously in included as well.
>> What what I use ex is exactly what you
see. What I use is volume spread
analysis. That is the relationship
between price and volume. So if I see
like you were saying here sellers, okay,
>> trying to push the market down
>> but they are punching a wall. They are
not going through.
>> So what they are doing they can either
stay still inside the position if this
movement stop them out.
>> Yeah.
>> The market will accelerate of course.
Okay. So what I see is that this
aggression is the first one in all this
movement that print this huge candle.
>> Yeah. Why staying in a movement that is
saying we are getting the control is
like getting inside a world and being by
the side of the weak
>> parties like doesn't make sense. And
from here you can see that participation
is mainly by the sellers.
>> Yeah.
>> I want to show you something. I want to
clear a little bit and get back remember
how the volume is inside this area.
Yeah. Okay. Let's remove for one second
the big trades and let's go here.
You agree that this is a compression
area?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Let's print it.
You see that the market is not accepting
below the value area because what
happens is that here is transaction
incorrectly but every time they go deep
discount buyers enter aggressively and
get back the the position here. This is
exactly what's happening. Let's go on
the today price action.
And so we we saw one New York
>> and we watch one London session and this
is not a normal London session. This is
a London session. This is after the
bombing of Iran. So the volatility it's
even higher than a usual London session
because the market needs to rebalance
this gap.
>> Same situation rates. So
if I tell you forget about everything,
it's here. Just tell me in which area
there is the major amount of delta
aggression from the buyers in which area
you can see.
>> Would it be the buyers you say?
>> Yes.
>> Exactly this one. And if you see
>> Yeah. I'm getting tapping in.
>> If you see this is exactly how you can
identify when it's an accumulation and
when it's a distribution.
>> Yeah.
>> This is where all the traders are
struggling like why accumulation
distribution. But how can I identify
objectively what's happening? If you see
from this level, aggression of buyers
catalyst.
>> Yeah, let's go down to the one minute.
We already in one minute. Perfect. We
activate the big trades again. Same
model. What we see?
Buyers aggressive catalyst. Catalyst
catalyst catalyst. Again, you see what
sellers are doing? They are trying to
push the market up down. But what's
happening? They're getting
anniated by buyers.
>> So if you get the profile as before from
the starting of the swing to the end of
the swing, what you can see? You can see
that volume is equally distributed here
and you start to have a low volume from
here. So in this case to follow the
exact mo model, you will be unfilled in
this position. Okay, let's go
educationwise on and see what's
happening and reading here
what you can do considering that you are
still in the same area. You see that
from here to here they create a new
dealing range new area. So you can do
just the same from here to here and you
can go deep dive inside this location.
>> Yeah.
>> Look where is the value area low and
look where is the low volume node.
You see this lack of volume here?
>> Yes.
>> So you have the low volume node
conceding with the value area low
conceding with
>> this is free money.
>> This is free money. You wait for
this candle. You put the stop loss here.
You target either because even if you
want to target
let's say here, okay, you are risking
per contract $160.
In the worst case scenario, if you want
to be out really fast, you are risking
160 to make 500. Yeah. Okay. So the
risk-to-reward is more than one to three
in this case. But this is the excursion
the market gives you. So you you see how
the risk to reward can get really huge
if you get in tune in the market.
>> Yes.
>> And the addition to the position can be
done every time that the markets create
a new eye. This a failed auction. It
doesn't break out. But then it break out
here. Okay.
>> To the to there. Yeah.
>> Again look zero volume here. like
>> from the profile
>> punching the wall
>> I will not get this trade because I
don't have aggression so it's not as
safe as this one
>> but again
the bias is completely fine and this is
the both of the model we saw the
reversion model and the trend following
model and the first time that I find out
this myself was a h aha moment
>> yes
>> because I just went to order fluency so
I can see before it happens
>> how the volume is developing
>> and also small exercise when the market
gets taken back in control by sellers.
>> Mhm.
>> All these small volume then huge
aggression from sellers but look also
where the market reacts when it comes
back.
>> What is doing now? This is actual price
action. We are not charting the past.
>> Yeah. sellers in control where they will
find the first problem when they get
back to these aggressive buyers.
Otherwise, they will continue to push
the market down in this case.
>> And when you see this case, it can be a
punch on the wall because sellers try to
push it down, but buyers protect the
level. And if you see it closely, what
is developing is a trend following
condition because we are going after all
this balance, we are going out of
balance. This is the first breakout.
>> Yeah.
>> And they can go back to the previous
point of control. So they have a long
room to go here. And you will notice I
don't know if it will happen live that
if this level get tapped back it
accelerate because sellers are adding to
their position. For now it is out of
balance print and it's going to
rebalance to the pock because it didn't
>> it was not a successful breakout.
>> Yes,
>> that's the reason I say always trend
following or reversal. Wait for the
second drive. Don't take the first drive
because you can get tap in in a fake
out.
>> Yeah,
>> that's it. It's not difficult. But I
know it's a lot of information for the
audience for the first time, but
>> I think it's a lot cleaner than some of
the order flow breakdowns I've seen
before.
>> They just make it hard to not let people
understand.
>> I mean different platforms as well um
you can make it like so in this case
with the what we would call the the
bubbles for example but in terms of
execution large orders. Yes.
>> So if you filter filtered it so that it
only shows specific size of orders.
>> Exactly. specific size because you can
take it on and off as well.
>> You want to filter out the noise. No,
you want to see what actual
>> big orders are doing is the same concept
as uh commitment of traders for long
term.
>> You are just watching the the
participants that matter. If you move
one contract in mini, I'm not interested
in it. Just you can do what the you
want. But if someone is adding 100
contract on NASDAQ on one minute, it's
interesting.
>> Mhm.
>> Like the momentum
>> in terms of price getting to this point,
this high that we were talking about
here cuz as we were talking about
potential trades from down here.
>> Yes.
>> Uh what is there anything to the left as
to why price is reacting at this area? I
think there's a high to the left that we
were originally looking at.
>> You want to see where we are going.
Is there anything of significance in
this area where it would lead you?
>> We we don't need to to guess. Okay.
>> So, let's remove this part so we don't
know exactly where it was. Let's print
it
and let's go down here. Okay.
>> Mhm. Now, let's clean all the noise
As you can see in all this area the
value area is this one. So I will make
white the value area.
So this is when the market considering
all the profile
>> the comprehensive profile also of the
gap is when it's getting expensive for
market participants. Okay.
>> But if we get deeper we notice that the
biggest peak of sellers you see this
one. Okay. So this level can be
something
interesting from sellers perspective
wise
the market reacted from this value area
is distributing and as I was saying to
you probably is going back to the PC
>> that is this level and it's exactly
overlapping with the big volume trades.
>> Yes. So
the probability of a follow-up short
>> now it's higher in this case
>> even if they get before back to the pock
and then redist red distribute back down
but I want to show you also here
>> from this profile
>> was it understandable that this was the
reaction level from the delta that is
developing
>> yes because this pro this supply is the
real way way of plotting supply
>> you are just watching volumewise when
there is the most amount of executed
trades not limit but executed trades
this mean that the auction get too much
expensive
>> they want to sell off and in this case
and they sell off till here then what
happened here exactly is that
>> the price get too low
>> Mhm. to sell because it's getting cheap
again to buy also for buyers you know.
>> So from this perspective we have this
buyers trying to aggressive
no follow up sellers no follow up. So we
are getting inside the decision range.
Mhm.
>> The first one that will get breakout,
you will see a catalyst in that
direction and probably the first level
is this one.
>> Cuz even in this case, for example, if
this was to break the high,
>> even though we might not be looking to
trade this, but if we were looking to
make a prediction, would we then break
the high and then look to go to uh the
high of the value area potentially or
even the the previous
>> I will say the P
>> P first. uh like distribute against the
PC and then if you need to refine an
area where you can probably see a
reaction I will say this supply here
like you were saying
>> not because it's the best level to react
because the best level to react is the
value area high
>> but because uh uh this delta here it's
really reliable on how much aggression
is it giving.
Hey guys. So, we've had obviously the
biggest nightmare you can imagine on
Chart Fanatics. As you saw there, we
were middle of screen recording, storage
issue, uh screen recording cut. We cut,
no problem. We came back, uh we pressed
screen record, but something happened.
However, what we're going to do to make
up for it, one, we're going to break
down exactly what happened step by step
after the fact, no problem. But we're
going to actually wait until New York uh
open and then we're going to do some
live uh price reading then. um you know
at an actual time where Fabio does trade
and we'll be looking at specific things
as well. So, we're excited for that. Hey
guys, we're back. I promised you New
York session. We are 30 minutes before
just under 30 minutes before the session
open. Um we can recap exactly what
happened uh since we left as well and uh
super excited for this first time ever.
I don't think I've ever seen a video
where it's done this where it's
educational showing the concepts but
then actually trading it live thereafter
and you know calling out price
essentially. I'm very excited. No one
better then of course with Fabia.
>> Yes. Do you want to win seven figures in
challenges without having to do anything
at all? Seems too good to be true,
right? Well, at propertrader.com that is
exactly what is possible. You are buying
proper challenges anyway. Well, at
propertrader.com, not only will you get
the best prices and be able to compare
your proper challenges, but by
automatically using the code PFT, you
automatically get entered into this
weekly giveaway where you can win over
seven figures in challenges. All your
favorite prop firms are on proper.com.
Just like brokerbacked proper Atmos
funded, backed by Torrex. The fact that
they are brokerbacked means that you
have stability and security when it
comes to your payout. Once your payouts
are approved, traders are receiving them
in less than five minutes. They have
instant funding, one-step accounts, and
two-step accounts, meaning that whatever
type of challenge you prefer, they have
one for you. Thousands of traders over
the last couple months have joined Atmos
Funded, and over $200,000 have been paid
out in just the last 6 weeks alone. You
can get massive discounts on their 50 to
200K accounts and even bigger discounts
on their 5 to 25K accounts. Use the code
PFT on screen right now. But not only do
we have Atmos, we also of course have
Apex Trader funding. The largest futures
firm in the entire industry with up to
90% off using the code PFT, up to 20
accounts, and up to 6 million in futures
funding. You can also find Alpha
Capital, who also have one-step
challenges, two-step challenges, and
three-step challenges just for you. So,
no matter what type of challenge you
prefer, they have an option. And not
only that, we have Funded Next, one of
the top three CFD firms in the industry.
And again, an exclusive offer through
PFT. Check it out on screen. The link
for popfirmtrader.com is in the
description below. So, make sure you
check that out. And remember, use code
PFT at checkout at all your favorite
firms and automatically be entered into
the massive 7 figure giveaway every
single week. Now, let's get back into
the episode. So, we are here. We are
stuck in a range. We are on fair value.
Before we treat to do a recap, we saw
this punch to the wall, the aggression
of the seller, the follow up to the
balance area. And now there is the first
piece of information that we can get
that was not present before is this
punch of aggressive sellers without
follow follow up getting to the discount
level getting back inside the range. So
I think as I was saying before that this
high for the day it's something that
will get destroyed probably at the
beginning of the market open because the
structure that I see now even if I have
the information that sellers are getting
aggressive and building up here the
structure of the market that we never
need to forget is still bullish and as
you can see this is the level where the
majority of aggression is getting this
is the level where sellers are getting
really aggressive.
There is a dry up of volume and as you
can see a low volume node. This is
exactly what the market printed here. So
in 20 minutes we have the first setup
probably that can either be breakout
here breakout and test if the volume is
supporting it. Otherwise we can get a
buy from the discount but this will be
more risky from here. You can see that
they are starting to fight because it's
pre-market opening. This is the reason
why I never trade pre-market opening
because you see the battle but you don't
know who will win it because we are
stuck in a range. So from the data that
we have seen here the size of the bubble
is controlled by sellers. So it means
and also the price is going down. So
>> they are winning the battle but we need
to remember that we have these big boys
here ready to protect the price. M
>> so at the moment I don't feel confident
to to check any any setup. I prefer that
we check closely. We should expect the
first drive
not at
market opening but 5 minutes before and
people that trade will see it often like
they are preparing the dealing range
testing on the market opening and then
getting in the direction. So what I
expect is that if
we are going to get really long,
>> yeah,
>> this eye needs to be taken before 20
minutes. So I mark this eye
>> if we're going to get long.
>> If we're going to get long. Now
>> I will create some scenario that are all
rule based.
>> Okay.
>> So let's remove this one
>> and let's make some scenario. So the
first scenario is that these sellers are
going to get absorbed. Okay.
>> Now if these sellers are short here,
probably they are going to get
liquidated here.
>> If the price during market opening spike
ups really hard, they are forced to
close their position. Closing a cell
will create more momentum long.
>> Okay.
>> Watching how much they are pushing short
>> makes me think that they are either
closing long position from here. either
they are getting some scalp pre-market
opening and price will get back to this
level uh 21822 before skyrocketing long.
If we need to be conservative or it's
the only setup is break out here test
the level only when you have a closure
of the candle we go back to 1 minute.
>> Yeah.
>> So we get the real execution and uh the
market now will prepare the setup for
the market session open. So aggressive
sellers this can be seen also at what
traders call fake out. So the fake move
before the opening and then collapsing,
not collapsing but rising up. And as you
can see, let's make a comparison. The
sides of the ball, the red ball, it's
bigger, right? Yeah.
>> But the result is really bigger. Like
with small volumes, buyers are getting
better results. If you see here,
>> so it's really important to see to plot.
This is something that I do often to put
a profile from the first ball to the
last ball. Okay? Like this. and check
who is going out.
I show you. We can always hide the
trades.
>> So you have only raw price action and
volume distribution and you can see the
sellers are not yet managing to close
their candle below the value area low.
So we are still even in a small time
frame and a small data range we are
still consolidating and compressing.
Yeah, the direction of the market is not
clear at the moment and uh usually
it gets really clear the direction for
the day
from 15 minutes to 30 minutes inside the
opening of the session. Cut. So it's
normal. It's totally normal what's
happening. Now they are loading
position. Now this one it's already a
big information for me. If this candle
stays like this and we take this high,
you can also try the the aggressive
setup. But we will only use the model
that I explained before. We will not
because people can get confused with too
much information. So let's let's go
easy. But as you can see, they put
aggressive sellers here, but the
followup it's almost zero. Why? Because
again, the buyers are protecting this
position. Yeah. And in the overall bias
if you see what's happening at the
moment is that from the previous range
of compression the market tried to break
out.
>> Yeah.
>> But it failed. So structure-wise we are
still long.
Now let's remove all the unnecessary
data and let's put the big trades. And
one thing you mentioned was that those
big trades
>> pre previously when we were looking at
the charts,
>> there wasn't that many because we
weren't in session yet. The session had
>> getting huge.
>> And you said like when we're in New York
session, you're going to see it like a
so much and we're not even in the
session just yet, but you can already
see an increase.
>> You know what I like about this about
these tools and these platforms that
volume is pro um bulls are proportional
to volume. So
>> when there is too much volume and not
clear direction, your market get floated
by bulls. So it's not visible the price
and you are forced to stay out because
you cannot see what's happening behind.
So it's like an insurance on your hand
to stay calm like do not do anything
>> and uh what I would really love and the
my favorite setup possible is when
market explode following up by green
level and you can just jump in at the
first level when it pulls back in a low
volume node. This is amazing. Now this
is totally normal and this is the reason
I strongly advise not to trade like 10
minutes before the session, 20 minutes
before the session because you will be
liquidated and then maybe your direction
was right. Yeah.
>> But it will be up by
>> volatility. This is something that not
all traders take into account the
volatility range can change by session.
So a model that works for runon session
it's not guaranteed that will continue
to create alpha and generate revenue in
the new year session. An example of this
is the mean reversion model. You will
see now if we apply m reversion model
here we will be get destroyed by market
and you will get also slippage because
it's normal.
>> It's compressing here.
>> Still the entity of the sellers is huge
but there is no followup. What does it
mean that someone is absorbing this
order
>> and if they are absorbing this order
>> if you watch only color you say it's
controlled by sellers but I still have
my narrative long still think that we
are going to get the high for the day
momentum is building up we are getting
10 around 10 minutes 13 minutes before
the session and as I told you we are
going you expect that high to take
>> to target the design now what can we
expect when we target like
>> explosion like
>> acceleration like we were seeing before.
Why?
>> Because these huge orders
>> are getting close. They don't want to be
before session.
>> Yeah.
>> With this heavy and being in the wrong
direction. Yeah.
>> So they tried to anticipate the fall
down of price but as you can see it's
not going really good for them.
>> So we are going to see when the market
approach exactly this high.
as of now still not getting broken.
What we want to see is this green balls
here like we did in all the previous
situation.
>> Yeah,
>> this is a good setup for follow-up.
Aggressive setup if we want to cover
everything. One aggressive setup can be
the anticipation
on the first ball with a stop loss below
the sellers to get to the high. But it's
a setup that you are still trading the
noise.
>> Yeah.
>> So something that you cannot expect will
have the same way rate of a good frame
trend following setup.
So you see when you get back inside the
range the balls are so big that you
cannot even see what's happening
>> and this is keeping you away from
interacting with the market like
transactioning
>> in terms of like what parameters if any
or settings have you put to identify
these large orders? Is there specific
>> for Yes. Yes. For the five minutes and
one minutes for New York session you can
use 30 contract as a filter. 30 contract
and um um during London session you can
go with 20. It's it's pretty accurate
like this
>> and
>> so the larger it is that mean it's more
than 30
>> the more maybe these are 100 contract
got like so big and I created like this
proportional so you don't need to click
on it see how much contract but you
immediately see that there is a big sell
aggression there got
>> like it's
>> see sell I was expecting that the I buy
would but sellers so they are still
keeping here
>> why before session they are still
keeping here because the direction is
not clear who want to transaction here
when you can get whip side high, whip
side low, you're out of the market.
Yeah,
>> you are getting liquidated with every
direction. So,
>> and these buyers or sellers, they can be
anyone, right? They could be, you know,
a retail trader with large capital or it
could be your funds or whatever it may
be.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> Now, an information that we cannot unsee
is that at the eye, they are still
loading short even if the market is
going to push the eye. So the the
narrative it's a little bit shifting
because if this low gets taken we have
this breakout
>> is interesting also the short till here
why I will not take this position
because the whole picture is long so why
should I take one to one risk-to-reward
when I can wait and get a 1 to 3 1 to
four 1 to5 this is the the model we need
to to use and the model is keeping you
you out out of lot of trades like
>> we need to be evidence based and
oriented on a large number of sample.
Executing 25,500 sample in a world cup
can give you the taste of what's worth
to do and what's not worth to do because
maybe one times out of 10 now we go
short. Yeah.
>> But all the other times the seller
getting destroyed and the test is here
and you just lose.
>> Yeah.
>> To get so small movement. That's
>> because I think that's one thing that's
universal across any trading strategy is
that
>> you focus on quality. Yes.
>> Rather than just anything that could
work or you know this has a chance of
working and it could work one out of 10
times or whatever it may be because I
feel like that one time you do take and
it does work. It always just reinforces
you the next time to take it again.
Right. Take it again. Take it again. And
you know it might work two three times
if you're lucky and then the next 20 30
times it's not going to work but you're
still thinking on those two or three
times it does. Exactly.
>> Versus when you have an actual plan,
>> you know, quality trade playbooks and
you follow those playbooks,
>> that's where your consistency will come
from, your longevity will come from as a
trader. That's where you're really going
to start to scale your journey. And
scale your journey doesn't mean that
it's going to happen fast. But what it
means is you will have progress. And the
funny thing is it will happen faster
than the alternative of
>> yes
road is the fastest road. So it's always
like this. Now what I'm doing in
precession is marking up the biggest
delta volume.
>> Yeah.
>> So I want to know
>> so delta volumes on the left right?
>> Yes.
>> I want to see at the market opening
which level I can see that are getting
tapped. I want to use different colors
where use just deep red for this one.
And for the buy part,
I take the swing on the low
>> and I see what's the level with most
amount of volume. That clearly is this
cluster of by volume.
>> Yeah,
>> to be honest, there is also this one is
smaller but is still here.
These are the level that we can see in 7
minutes. get
>> and from here we already know what to
expect when to expect it.
>> So do you sit on the 5minut time frame
when marking out your analysis when it
comes to execution wise
>> one minute? Yeah.
>> Yes. Clearly like this.
Now chart is only showing us the levels
color. We can see the aggression and we
can see the actual execution. So now we
don't need 5 minutes anymore. We can
just go down to 1 minute.
Can zoom in. You see how much they are
big when you go here. You can see
clearly that
>> this aggression at the moment is getting
completely absorbed.
>> Yeah,
>> this got absorbed.
>> Do you ever think like for example in
this case this person tried to sell, got
absorbed.
>> Could that be the same person like
stacking into a trade or is that not
sort of how? You cannot know if it's the
same operator but for sure you know that
these traders are in draw down
>> and there is still interest in the
sellers. So what I can see is that they
are trying to build a sell position
>> and they will be forced to close if
market volatility spikes.
>> So if I get these aggressive buyers and
all these sellers needs to close the
position we arrive here the market
opening
>> and we are closed because it's 324. This
is the first moment I would expect. And
so in this case, if price did break
above this level,
>> you're not interested in trading that to
the next level. You're interested once
price gets to that level.
>> Exactly. Okay. Exactly. Because I I need
to see.
>> But would you say it's still important,
sorry, to have this context even if
you're not looking to trade to that next
level, it's still important to
understand what's going on
>> because you are training for the
procession procession and creating a
narrative. So when you know how to do it
um you are still
understanding with your subconscious
mind what's happening because you need
to be really fast.
>> Yeah.
>> And you need to reason fast and if you
don't do it and you do only for your
setup
>> on 15 second and 1 minute is not enough
fast to then execute at the right
moment. You see how much volume and
interaction is starting 5 minutes before
like I told you not at 30 5 minutes
before they are preparing the order from
what we can see here this is a huge
information aggressive sellers still to
this level buyers with better results
all these are getting absor absorbed
this is not my narrative getting wasted
or this is my narrative getting
confirmed
>> so even more I should expect now that
either from here or either from Here we
reaccumulate in the last 5 minutes and
we shoot up. All these sellers are in
pain. They need to close and the market
create an expansion move up.
>> Okay,
>> it breaks. I can take the long from
there and I'm done for the session. Like
>> one one setup with high win rate.
But understanding the narrative before
makes you also understand market
participants how they are thinking and
if they are proven wrong.
>> Yeah.
>> With this amount of contract you cannot
hold anymore. Even if you have a
millionaire account you need to close
sooner or later.
>> Yeah. Are these market executions or
they
>> market execution not limits? Like I
never watch limits. Like you can get to
feel a taste of the market but
>> because the limits apparently they can
>> they can cancel. Yeah, they cancel. So
they what do they call it? Spoofing is
it? Is that what?
>> Yeah, they call spoofing like putting
order to create market pressure then
removing. It's manipulating the
perception of other market participants.
>> But with execution just these are
executed market. There is someone that
is with huge sell you know there if you
if it close you see it.
>> Yeah you see. So uh in this case
so in the first minute of market opening
you will not see the chart
>> it would get balls
>> it's it will get like something like
this
>> does does this uh large aggressive buyer
that failed up here does that make you
>> yeah you are getting good you are
getting this is an aggressive buyers
that created a failed auction
>> so the buyers here got like they tried
really hard like this but the sellers
won here
>> in this battle also the sellers won.
Okay.
>> Because they are transactioning down.
Yeah.
>> So in this that's the reason you wait
for your confirmation and you don't jump
here because even if the bias is long
you don't know if they will reach here
or the second level that attract.
>> I only know that I only know that I want
to be in if this level gets broken.
>> Yeah. So, let's see what they do. 3
minutes before
a setup for a scalp position. A little
bit more risky is if these sellers don't
have a follow-up and got absorbed by
buyers shooting up here. But this is a
risk position. But this can be I show
you only to to give to the audience a
taste.
this one like risking $300 and getting
$1,100 is not a stupid position. It's
just a position that you are taking
inside the noise.
>> Yeah,
>> I can take this kind of position only if
I'm sitting in profit for the day.
>> Okay.
>> Like it's it's not uncommon that I take
them but I need to use profit and not
use market um like um account equity.
>> Yeah. Because
>> using house money, right? Yeah. like
before I need to take money from the
market then I can take this kind of
trades
>> the win rate it's lower on this but if
you consider the risk-to-reward it's uh
like one to four
>> so it's it's pretty good I just put this
risk to reward because I want to let you
understand that if these sellers fail
they will catalyze up
>> now I need the first minute if this one
gets broken the setup is not valid but
if in market open at um 3:30 you recover
this level
>> like and this one gets not broken. This
is the target.
So
let's see how the market will behave
from what we are seeing at the moment.
Sellers one.
>> Yep.
>> Sellers one. Buyers one.
>> Yeah.
>> Here. So you are getting a bias and a
level that start to get interesting.
Let's zoom in. It's not visible. So
considering the platform, you should not
interact in this position even before
because
>> you can't see. You cannot see what's
happening here
cuz the first execution can be taken
after market open and we are still
before. So one trigger can be the break
of this eye for example for a long. So
now that we are getting inside if this
eye get broken a really aggressive
position can be entering at the break of
this with the stop loss here targeting
the high and I think it's even more than
uh as a riskto-reward even more than one
to to four. It's 1 to5 probably. So
market is opening. They didn't break the
high. So no position gets executed at
the moment. Now we are in the second buy
area.
>> Yeah.
>> So we need to check how the volume is
behaving at the moment. Now these
traders are in profit.
>> Yes.
>> All these buyers that position themsel
before the opening needs to close
position. This will bring price lower.
>> All this movement is made by them.
Now, now that we are in market opening,
we can start to take position or do
analysis that we can actually use. So,
let's see the the first information that
we have is that sellers still want this
battle at the moment
>> and they are getting stopped only here.
Okay. So, still in the noise remember
our rules till we don't get here the
premium setup is not executed.
>> Yeah. So inside here what can be
something interesting for us? The first
information that we can have is sellers
really aggressive here that don't have a
follow-up short. Yeah.
>> So if this candle start to get populated
by a lot of sellers but get back here.
>> Yeah. This can be a long
>> but again it's a long that you can you
take inside market ranging. So let's
just wait here
>> because you had a you have a level
beneath this right and towards the low.
>> Uh I think the main level of the buyers
are getting destroyed.
>> Yeah.
>> So the only reason I can engage in a
risky position here is if this one prove
me that it's a fake out.
>> How can they prove me that it's a fake
out? They need to recover all this.
>> Yeah. This one needs to be a full week
and they need to break up again from
this high.
If they don't do this, you see sellers
are completely dominating this market at
the moment. So not engaging here.
You know in price action you can try
this long because you don't see this. So
you see you think
>> it's it's retracing. I can buy this
count. No, you you you
>> probably think like break and retest the
level.
>> You know, this is this is something that
if you are price action trader, you
cannot know because you are not good but
because you don't see that they are
willing to sell stronger at lower point.
>> Yeah.
>> So the auction is getting short.
Which one is the first level we can
protect? We need to go with the profile
on everything they build also during
London session, not only during the
range,
this big area
and this low volume node like also
Carmen is doing. This is a low volume
node and this is the delta. Yeah,
>> this is the last protection level. If
this one is breaking, they are
recovering this cell and they are
collapsing
and he's in in that scenario what would
you do? Would you just then
>> in the scenario that they get sell my
narrative will change because they break
a balance level not on the up on the
downside. Okay.
>> So my day is short.
>> Yeah.
>> If my day is short I will still use the
same model just I will not get long I
will get short.
>> Gotcha.
>> Like my long day gets activated if we
break this.
>> Yeah. My short day at the same time gets
activated if we break the compression
range that is all this range. If they
arrive here we can try something but
here there is something that is
undeniable.
>> They are on this level. They are pushing
out but I don't see a lot of follow-up
shot.
>> Yeah.
>> So here the buyers you see how many
volumes
>> so much. Yeah.
>> Here the buyers are protecting it limit
orders. So either they slice through it,
but if they start to recover and they
get back inside the range, this is a a
setup that also Patrick Neil is using
with volume.
>> And you see the good part about volume
is keeping you up.
>> Is keeping you out of the market when
it's not ready
>> here because let's go again to the
narrative here. If it breaks the low,
yeah, we get long. It continue down.
Okay, here. If it breaks the high, we
can go here. Why? Because if the volume
don't does this, this means that the
sellers are controlling all this market
movement.
>> Yeah.
>> You don't need to predict. Just need to
see what's happening here is the first
time for the market opening where buyers
are protecting a level.
>> Yeah.
>> In an interesting in an interesting
situation. So this one can be the first
long position if it gets confirmed by a
little bit of buy aggression. At the
moment it's only sell. Yeah. The moment
is only sell. So now the only thing to
do is wait what what they can do. Now
one position that gets really
interesting is the squeeze of the trapid
sellers.
>> Mhm.
>> When is the squeeze of the trap sellers?
When you recover all the aggressive
sellers. Yeah.
>> They are getting fake out. So they are
willing to close the position and the
market is accelerating high. You know
>> let's see what is happening here. This
is the first footprint of long yeah
>> position from the level that we saw.
Still someone can think why you don't
take a long position here because at the
moment if you see who created the swing
like we were talking before is
completely dominated by sellers.
>> Yeah,
>> this is a really risky position. If we
start to get back here
we can take position on the breakout
with stop loss below the level. But
remember the model is one. You need to
break and test this level. Otherwise,
you just stay out.
>> When this level gets broken, the game
start. You can add the position, you can
follow up, you can do a lot of things.
Now, I want to show you how much it's
useful to see this volume in higher time
frame
like five minutes.
From here, it's clear. It's clear
because you see we agree that this is
the low volume node. Okay. The profile
distribution achieved the value area
low.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. So, we are on the value area low.
The sellers didn't got a follow through.
They took the low.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. And created a failed auction.
People call this manipulation. They try
to break out and they failed.
>> This is the reason we will get here.
>> Well, it's what you said um you know
before the open is going to set up
>> and then it will whipsaw take out one
side. This is a model like the only
things is that I don't get
>> inside when they are
>> like so aggressive.
>> So my role is not to predict when they
will stop. I just wait that they
complete this movement. You see all this
was a fake.
>> The narrative is still buy.
>> Mhm.
>> All this movement gets absorbed one with
which the narrative when we break this
level. We broke this level. No. So we
are still buy.
If you want to clear the position and
for the New York session get a better
tune of the market, you can raise 240
>> at the contract size.
>> The contract and you will it the
situation will be a lot clearer.
>> You see?
>> Yeah.
>> Situation now it's clear buyers got more
than 40 contract here. They are just
putting a lock and say below this level
you don't go like you you try to sell
with two I absorbed everything and they
are recovering all the buy. Now all
these sellers need to close the
position.
>> Yeah.
>> Which then causes a squeeze
>> squeeze like if all these sellers close
the position the market is jumping and
when it gets to this level you see the
acceleration that we saw before but
short. Yeah.
>> Like the opposite.
In the video that I made with Andrea,
all the setup that I took are based on
this model like squeezing the other
part. Yeah.
>> To get the acceleration and be
immediately break even.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Be able to move at break even
really fast.
>> Would you say that is one of the
necessary skill sets when scalping at
this level?
>> Yes. like uh being fast and also
creating shortcut on your platform.
>> Would you say that you always have been
like been able to move at speed as a
trader or is that something you had to
train?
>> No, we are we are we are human reads. I
will be really honest. Sometimes I made
big errors like um you scale inside the
position but you scale you you don't
notice that you are scaling not by one
mini contract a time but we are scaling
with five contracts. There is a huge
amount on NASDAQ like one contract is
really heavy
>> and you need to find a good way to scale
out and you are with like in scalping
you need to be fast and sometimes you
still make errors.
>> Yeah. Um
>> because a lot of the time there will be
human errors at that point right and
then then with this volatility look what
what the market did as I told you before
taking the high taking the low
>> and then being at the starting point
like in the first 10 minutes of the
session we didn't do anything we just
liquidated the low liquidated the high
>> that's the reason you don't engage
before
now I want to show you these sellers are
selling this momentum yeah with zero
results
Now we are getting back to this. When we
get back to this, someone will need to
cover their position.
>> Yeah.
>> When they need to cover the position,
the momentum will start to build up.
>> So let let's see what they do. Still my
narrative didn't change. The only thing
that could change my narrative is the
breakout of the level.
>> Still compressed inside here.
And we recovered also the major delta
point here. This means that we are above
the strong selling level of the
distribution. And if we are above here,
we are also above
the value area high and you remember
before the reaction that the market had
on the value area low. Yeah.
>> Like it completely used this as a pivot
before collapsing down. Yeah.
>> The same is for up like there is an
overlap of this area
>> and
now I think they are
>> so aggressive. If you wanted to be
aggressive, these are, you know, this
was a trade at the low you could have
taken, but again, it's like
>> it's not wrong, but
>> it's super super aggressive during that
time window that really isn't ideal.
>> This one you should not expect more than
40% we rate. So, you can take it, but
remember you are trying to take a
falling knife.
>> Yeah, a lot of times you will get cut
and you are buying the contrarian
momentum. So you are trying to stop the
price with the big market participants
>> after a lot of test and here it's more
easy to who is winning the battle. If
this low gets broken sellers are
winning. If this eye gets broken buyers
are winning the battle. Okay. Now you
know who won the battle. Now you can
engage.
>> Yeah.
>> Don't try to anticipate.
This is the main reason why a lot of
traders they try to anticipate what the
market is doing before the market does
it. and they get so attached to their
narrative that they are not willing to
change. As I told you, my narrative was
long from the beginning. The market did
an aggressive selloff. I was ready to
change my narrative and say from this
moment, if it breaks, I start to search
for short.
>> Okay.
>> I'm not marrying my position. I don't
care.
>> But you have specific levels that
invalidate your buys.
>> Yes.
Getting excited.
>> It's not so big the volatility today to
be honest. We are on the 5 minutes. I
think they are waiting if there is a
news of the other of their bombing
because
>> yeah so for context over over the
weekend today's Monday over the weekend
the US had bombed Iran in three
different sites. We gapped I believe
lower on ENQ. This is ENQ right? So we
gapped lower% the gap
>> we recovered the gap uh which we then
started recording earlier. We then
actually sold off and then recovered
again. So we're kind of in a range at
the at this current stage.
>> The squeeze gets completed here.
>> Yeah.
>> Like if they attack this eye and all
these are squeezed.
>> So here we can expect.
>> So it would be similar to what we were
looking at over here and
>> we saw this here. We saw this here
>> and they build momentum. Now the squeeze
that you see in London, it's
>> much less. Yeah. Less
>> the squeeze that you can see here is
three times this candle.
>> It's pretty aggressive.
>> Mhm. And what is it that you do when you
are you know active like say is in a
different setting we're recording and
everything even though you're going
through the same motions but when you
are waiting for these 10 15 for the
price to get to the right areas for you
do you still sit and watch or do you
have it up maybe some alerts and you're
doing other things
>> you can put alert on levels now
considering that I don't want to
transact inside here my first alert will
be here so just here
>> yeah first alert will be on
>> otherwise you get the temptation
Yeah, like I I've been I've been tapping
and now he's controlling himself. Yeah.
>> Uh the temptation to to get because here
it was really clear that the auction was
failing. A lot of aggression and no
follow up. But
>> it's not your model like
>> you are trying to put some intuition
inside the model that is already proven
to make money.
>> Yes. And
>> would you say that when you first
started learning uh and to to really
look at the market in this way, would
you say that you fall guilty sometimes
in the beginning of as you said trying
to use intuition and trying to maybe
overpredict and over trade almost
because you feel like okay I I can see
these sellers or I can see these buyers
and you start taking executions outside
of your model.
>> Yes, of course you know the Dunning
Krueger effect.
>> Mhm. when you introduce in your mind a
new concept you think you understood
everything like if I introduce now order
flow to a price action trader you will
say oh it's so easy like there are bolts
I take there are no bolts I don't take
no it's not like this so in the
beginning when I introduced it and my
model was this and they see aggression
and not follow up even if the model is
not completed and it's not I say but why
it's free money I jump in and then I say
when you journal you understand the
error that you did so when Your mind is
cold. You understand what's the real
error. Not before.
>> Yeah.
>> They are starting to squeeze. You see,
they try to break out the eye. A lot of
buyers aggression, but the sellers still
are pushing down limit orders like punch
on the wall from the buyers.
>> But the fact that they already reach the
eye, it means that the sellers are not
protecting the level anymore. So for
example, let's say if we at this point
we see buyers let's say we don't close
above
>> and is our likely scenario from here
probably to get to here
>> and then see again if buyers or sellers
went around.
>> Exactly. Yes. Why? Because this is the
level of protection and uh the candle is
still not closed. So this is still
building position. But if you start to
see rejection this is a level that you
can revisit. Now the point is that if
you enter here where you put your stop
loss because you see how much is big
this candle if you want to be safe you
will put your stop loss here. It's not
worth it.
>> Yeah of course
>> like it's um that's what I was saying
when volatility expand
>> you need to make a lot of consideration
that you were not making in long session
because one candle in long session you
can go short here and protect you here
and it's okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Look here you need to protect here. It's
not worth
>> Yeah.
>> It's just not worth the trade.
And yet Troy will still take it.
>> Yeah.
>> Because of that as you say that that
trying to predict or try and say okay
this is what's going to happen.
>> It's broken. Yes. Okay. I engage. I can
start to engage
>> to go here if I have some profit for the
day.
>> Yeah.
>> Otherwise
>> no
>> this level we stop here. But you see
this buy here
>> getting no follow through.
>> Y
>> some trader that is getting new at order
fluency. Maybe I can try a short from
here to here. Okay. Where you put your
stop loss
>> here? Is it worth it? No. Completely.
No. You are risking more than you are
expected to.
>> Exactly. In terms of a position at the
high, you know, the one that we're
waiting for and looking for. Price
breaks above. We do our confirmation. We
get in. Do you already have a preset uh
target in mind? Uh or is it something
that will depend on once we've broken?
So the first target is the the one with
the highest win rate. It's the previous
daily high.
>> Okay.
>> So if the previous daily high was above,
we can go to checking. Now let's check
here because they are building.
>> They're building. Yeah.
>> And they are preparing the squeeze like
as you can see is the first time that a
candle can accept here. Now if this was
happening here, this is a trade. It's
happening inside. So still if they
accept here once this is a breaker test.
This is a real breakary test.
like covering yourself below the
aggression and going through the next
level and it's still 1 to three 1 to4
risk-to-reward ratio. Okay,
>> you see how much is different watching
only candle and watching the momentum
that created this candle to break out.
Yeah.
>> Like you know that this is the level if
you want to trade and retest you need to
protect yourself.
>> Yeah.
>> And the first target that makes sense is
the level that we considered before. We
are not reinventing the wheel. Now
considering that we still didn't reach
the high. I can go here and mark up the
previous daily high. We have a lot of
room. You see if this is the first
target, we have a huge risk to reward.
If it breaks here and test, it's 1 to
10, 1 to 20.
Now
sell is trying to
>> stop back in. Yeah. Mhm. Failing.
>> Failing.
>> So let's recap what happened. The
narrative was long from the beginning.
Yeah, before getting us the opportunity
to be right, the market took the low.
>> Why? He revisit deep discount area. Then
he validated the first level of squeeze.
A good squeeze is when you approach the
level and you see aggression and at the
same time you see follow up from price.
This is a good squeeze.
>> Yeah.
>> These sellers are forced to close
position here and what they will create
more and more momentum.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
when price did come down here because
obviously we're recording this and we're
live and what are your thoughts like
what's going through your head? Do you
feel when price is down here like oh you
know I I
>> I was thinking like no no I was thinking
to be honest that you will break the law
>> and I was already preparing my mind for
the narrative to be short for the day.
>> I only start to change my mind when all
these sell bubbles pop with this buy.
Yeah. And I see that all this have zero
effort
>> that one.
>> So I I trace this and I validated this
is a low volume node. It means that
there is not a lot of transaction here.
The first transaction is this level
where there is a huge delta on by
volume. Yeah, this is exactly what
stopped price this bunch of information
profile low volume node aggression and
lock in from buyers is something that
can validate. But as I told you I never
told you I will go long from here. Yeah,
>> because it's just too risky. Like you
can get lower. Now,
>> this one was the only position that I
told you if you are a breakout traders
and you want to take, you can take this
position and just trail your stop below
your bubbles. Okay? And take
>> if you were to buy there, where would
your stop be? Under the candle low.
>> If you want to buy here, your stop loss
can be below the Okay.
>> So, it's really aggressive. Like, let's
say that the market just test this
movement. Okay.
>> Mhm. and your stop loss can be below the
big orders.
>> Yeah.
>> So, it's a stop loss of $200 to make
600. It's one to It's not bad.
>> Yeah.
>> But it's still a position created by
market noise.
>> Yes.
>> Is still not my setup.
>> Still in the ranges.
>> For sure. There will be some order flow
trader that is profitable doing this.
>> Yeah. But I will never do this because
the probability that the market with the
volatility of New York session will get
back here and do this move movement.
Yeah.
>> And create just a week then you are
right on your position. But maybe it
creates a week is really high.
>> So in this case we were lucky. It fell
to the to the pip it rejected and when
if this breaks the low we are already
zero risk.
>> Exactly.
>> So you are fast. You are really
reasoning fast. But
>> if I had to advise to a friend would I
use this model? No. because it's it's a
lot of stress. Imagine that in one
minute on in five minutes you have to
trail on the next block you need to be
really fast. Imagine risky $5,000 on the
position.
>> Very true. Yeah.
>> You need gut.
>> But when the the range of the New York
session is clear and you have a breakout
of the compression, you have data
supporting this to the point that there
are a lot of studies about u initial
initial breakout. Mhm.
>> Like you know the model initial breakout
when mark um New York American equities
break out the low
>> or the high of the New York opening
there is a huge probability that they
will continue. So I'm using a structural
inefficiency of the market. Yeah.
>> Just timing it better than usual traders
because I have order flow but I'm not
reinventing the wheel.
>> Of course
>> is nothing exceptional about it. And
this is the fourth time that in this
timeline we come back to the level that
I told you and we still reject sellers
zero result. Buyers aggressive new
auction if it breaks this low risk zero.
>> Yeah. Like
>> it's incredible to witness. Now what do
you think to the the term or statement
that people make in terms of buy low,
sell high? Because in this case what
we're
>> buy low, sell high. It's uh I'm totally
opposite to it. That's what I'm thinking
>> cuz I was thinking like at the low there
where we you know I would look at and
I'm sure a lot of other people would be
like oh you put it long that would be a
great place to buy but as you say that
yes you could but on the most chances
>> no wait you can if you are like uh uh if
you know the fair value of the asset
like if I would be doing this for a car
that I already know the market price.
Yeah,
>> that that is stable the market price. I
can buy low and create my business
around it. But market there is not too
high of a price for one asset. Yes.
>> Because the asset price change
constantly,
>> you know. So is by law low compared to
what
>> exactly?
>> Low compared to option flow. It makes
sense.
>> Low compared to order flow. There is no
law. You are buying high. I will never
sell this movement. You see what it's
doing now? This one is already
zero risk.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Some minutes now starting to get
interesting for sellers because we are
reaching what the level that we mark out
4 hours ago and is still holding.
>> Mhm.
>> What would you expect you would you
expect price to or would you want price
to break through aggressively or would
you actually not mind if price reaches
the level, sells off a bit and then
breaks uh thereafter? was like the the
prime like the ideal scenario.
>> I expect the sellers to get destroyed as
what I told you from the beginning. I
expect aggressive market participant to
step in as soon as we reach this high.
>> A little bit of pullback and then
>> going uh going aggressive as I told you
by the first 15 to 20 minutes of the
session the direction is clear and it's
exactly 20 minutes for me. The direction
is clear.
>> Yeah. First position was breakout trades
to get the high but you are still in
line with statistic distribution. Why?
Because you are getting a movement.
>> Yeah.
>> When a level gets broken supported by
volume and you are getting out your
position before the level. Yes.
>> So you are not trying to you see if we
keep the target to the high it's already
rejecting. Maybe now we does a whips and
then explode.
>> Exactly. was amazing to see especially
for the fact that okay we didn't take
this position because didn't fit the
playbook
>> didn't fit the
>> we don't have the house money from
trading earlier for example to take the
risk
>> and the that's I think so important to
highlight because a lot of traders out
there think you have a bias anything
that fits that bias you take so in this
case for example you you let's say you
came in long
>> and you would take a long you try to
take a long at the low there you try and
take a long there you try any long
that's possible you try and take right
in reality you have your playbook.
>> It doesn't matter what your bias is. As
long as that playbook hasn't presented
itself, you do nothing right on your
hands.
>> I think they will get a lot of value
from conceptwise from these trades
because this is explaining exactly
>> sure it was beautiful cuz even that I
would say that that's not the it's not
the worst trade in the world, right?
It's it's with the bias.
>> It's one to three in three minutes like
it's worth it. Just
>> depends on your playbook. Yeah. all.
Yeah, it depends who you play with.
That's what I'm saying though. It's It's
incredible to be able to see. Okay, we
had a bias. Here's a trade opportunity.
Played out beautifully even with the
explanation as well in real time, which
is most important. Um, yeah, it's
phenomenal to see and we're excited to
see how we continue to push through.
>> Now, um, what we should expect here is
revisiting this area. Why?
>> Aggressive buyers
>> failed,
>> not holding failed.
We knew exact we placed our target
exactly where we should expect a
reaction. Now there are two question.
First question is
>> how much deep will be this retracement.
>> Yeah.
>> Second question is we want to be in a
long position if we get back here. No.
Why? Because it's still not clear the
dealing
>> till these big boys don't fail and says
because the good edge is that if this
big boys gets broken.
>> Yeah. This needs to close position and
if all these dealing regions getting in
suffer
>> we are skyrocketing high and you will
say how is it possible that we are
skyrocketing high if we have a situation
like this from global macro perspective
that's the good part about order flow
you the market already includes all the
information possible you need to read
what the market is telling you not
putting the preconcept of no it will not
do this because there is that no your
role is only to read the data
>> the market itself
>> the market itself there is no better
mentor than market
>> so is it the case normally then so we'll
see at this point this is a previous
auction where sellers had won
>> and in this case because we've seen
buyers try to step in fail get absorbed
we then would expect the previous
auction to be revisited to see who's
going to win that battle
>> and essentially it's a constant flow of
>> what is this as you say expens expensive
or is this cheap? Is this where buyers
are are happy to transact out and win
the transaction or sellers? And
therefore, we constantly have the next
play ready. The next play ready
according. So if for example instead of
us the buyers failing here and we
actually won
>> and we broke above.
>> Mhm.
>> We would then
as you said there would probably be a
squeeze.
>> Yes.
>> How would you let's say if that was to
take place?
>> Mhm. Where would you look to try and
enter if because a squeeze let's say a
squeeze takes place that' be quite
aggressive right it will be quite
aggressive it will be
>> with a lot of big trades inside I will
plot my profile
>> search for the first low volume node
jump in with a really tight stop loss
and get the explosion
>> okay got you
>> and this way you can get really fast one
two three one to five if you have five
art for the day you are done
>> what you need it's a beautiful trade
>> and the good part is that if You take
two stop loss. The stop loss is so small
>> that you can afford to take three or
four stop loss.
>> Yeah.
>> And you on average what do you look to
risk? Does it depend on the day or the
account that you're trading?
>> Usually I I risk 0.25% per trade because
I trade personal account.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh in the Robins cap I reach till
0.5% per trade. Uh sometimes when I get
above 100% of return I get to 1%.
Gotcha. But I will my role is always
keeping draw down low because commission
it's really heavy there. Yes. Like 600
execution per quarter can cost you 10
20% of the account. So it's like you
don't need only to make profit. You need
also to repay commission. So it's just
not not uh convenient to execute. What's
happening here?
>> We're seeing the buyers trying to trying
to break this level.
>> Yeah. They are getting aggressive to the
eye. What does it mean that they are
willing to pay higher price? Yeah.
>> For this asset. Yeah. So is it too
expensive to buy? No. Because if it was
too expensive, aggressive buyers will
not participate here. So it means that
still my narrative is buyer. Even if I
didn't break this level, I already know
what to expect for the day. Already
know. And we are getting ready for the
squeeze. The squeeze will be present
here. Look.
>> There you have it.
>> This is the squeeze. Now what can we
expect?
Really fast analysis.
This is the bunch of aggressive trades
that are populating this movement.
>> Y
>> I will not plot the profile because this
is all low volume node.
>> Yep.
>> They didn't transact efficiently. So the
first position that you can take here is
protected by this area. Okay. So if this
candle close and it's only five minutes
uh it can either give us a follow
through so break of the eye and we get a
retracement because remember we never
take the first drive.
>> Okay.
>> Because it can be a fake out.
>> You're on the confirmation. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> See it can be a fake out. It can be
absorbed and snapped back.
>> I'm getting too excited. I'm like yeah
execution. Let's get let's get in here.
But this is why you're the professional
and I'm the podcaster.
But it is incredible honestly uh to see
you know play by play
>> uh we can have a position here if it
breaks the low you can get the first
position of risk here targeting a one
to2 so we are risking 6 600 to make
potentially
double 1,200 and if we want we can also
trail our stop loss
>> to the to the high and the high is a
huge risk to reward if it achieves
leaves it. But our rule now is to put
our stop loss to risk zero as soon as
possible.
>> Of course. Yeah.
>> This
>> so this long executes if the high gets
broken.
>> Yeah. This execution can be on by stop
like
>> buy stop. Yeah.
>> If it uh breaks the high you can be
inside the position. Now this this makes
sense because we are protected by all
these big orders you know.
>> So as soon as this week gets taken you
are just inside and you are covered
here. Why? Because look look what's
happening here. If this okay we are
inside in this position. We are risking
$650.
If these sellers are getting aggressive
and we are getting anniated we want to
be out as soon as possible because it
means we are wrong.
>> Yeah. At the same time if we see these
sellers getting completely absorbed by
buyers in continuing up doesn't fail the
stop and we are
>> if we go above would you say that it
would uh would it cause a squeeze
because especially because of the size
of
>> understood how it works.
>> Yes.
>> So if we break above now for example and
we continue higher in terms of trailing
your stop would you be then trailing it
beneath?
>> It's not so difficult. No, it's not.
>> It is so interesting because as I was
saying to you earlier like I think a lot
of people have a huge misconception with
>> they think order flow it's hard.
>> Yeah.
>> Just order their flow is reading an
alphabet. You need to learn letters and
then that's it. But it's really strange
what's happening here because it's not
common that you have a breakout and you
don't test. They are leaving a huge low
volume node. The only thing I'm afraid
because consider that we are now in the
position is that in the test of the low
volume node they will spike out but we
we will take multiple position in this
case. Yeah. So they are pushing the eye.
What does it mean if they are pushing
the eye and make another drive? This big
boy needs to close the position because
he's losing. And if this boy needs to
cover himself, the squeeze can get
interesting.
See, just analyzing balls, not price.
>> These balls look
>> just a game of balls.
>> When they start overlapping, it kind of
looks like ICT's enigma, you know, like
>> this is how this is how it's really
going on. Yeah. But now
>> the algorithm is saying that we are
going to get long.
>> Mhm.
It's not orderful. It sound good.
>> It is incredible though. Honestly,
>> you can only understand where is price
because you watch this line. You see
this?
>> Exactly.
>> Exactly. It's so interesting honestly.
But I'd love to I do wonder, you know,
what the audience are thinking at this
stage. You know, what they would feel
trading this live, especially when we
were down at the low at the open when
you said that we'll see a shakeout. I
wonder how many people would probably be
looking to either uh short, probably
been stopped out already and trying to
revenge trade or get back in or like
what would that look like, you know, for
for a lot of people cuz I can imagine
>> down there a lot of people probably
would have been shorting shorting
shorting expecting, you know, a follow
through down
>> but then, you know, especially after the
gap's been filled as well, right?
Because a lot of people would assume be
gap filled in London, we're going to
then continue lower, right? Uh but as we
can see
>> but in what's good about what's what's
happening like the sellers the sellers
are getting completely destroyed then
soon
>> we have the
incredible
>> soon we have the we can put the stop
loss at break even we have a long way to
go still.
>> So at this stage would you have scale uh
moved the stop loss beneath the the red
uh the red bubble there? There's only
one reason I will not do it and they
will be happy to take a stop loss if it
snap back at me because there is low
volume low volume node like you they can
push a spike really fast and they get
liquidated in a really good position.
>> Got you. Yeah.
>> Like this position it's only one
contract
>> can give you 1,000. Look how much it's
pushing. Like
>> that makes sense. Yeah.
>> No, we got we enter here and we got one
lazer green line. You cannot expect
anything better as a trader because you
are just psychologically it's way better
than being included in this mess. No,
>> very true. Yeah, very very true.
>> It's time for us to put the risk to
zero. So now
>> So now even if it comes to low volume
node, it's fine because you've taken
zero
>> and you have a chance to reenter that.
>> Yeah.
>> Now you can play this game in a lot of
ways. You can scale in again.
>> Uh you can put this stop loss to break
even and use this amount of profit to
open another position because you have
another lock in here. What does it mean
lock in? This seems like the master card
logo but it's sellers getting
aggressive.
>> Yeah.
>> And buyers getting more aggressive than
that. Who is fall? You see they are
willing. Now when I tell you what does
it mean buy low sell high if they are
willing to pay a higher price to push
the price down. There is no discount.
There is no premium. Yeah. Like it's
it's just stupid the concept that they
are trying to push to the audience
because here the only thing the market
is telling you is that buyers are
willing to pay more to buy NASDAQ.
That's it. Yeah.
>> As simple as that. You don't need seven
screen. You don't need a huge amount of
tools. You are we are just watching the
real nature of the market. Orders not
candles.
So if you were to add there, would it be
a case where you want a close and then a
revisit?
>> Yes, in this case you will take profit
because it's already like half. It's
like 1 to 1.5 when it was here. So you
can just close and use the profit to
take another trade on the test.
>> Gotcha.
>> We are not doing this this model because
this low volume node scares me. Yeah.
And I'm really I don't want to say I'm
sure because I hope it will go good but
I know my my chicken I know my NASDAQ
and usually at the session it's just
give the first drive.
>> Yeah.
>> Pull back.
>> And create but we can just now we are
risk that's the reason also I got
aggressive with risk zero because we can
take it another trades otherwise use the
profit on the first one to take another
one that will be even better. What is
telling us the market now?
Just analyzing raw data, the buyers at
the top are not getting accepted. So
it's getting expensive.
>> Yeah.
>> If it get expensive, we should start to
see some sellers here.
>> Yeah.
>> And if we see sellers and they win the
battle, we are up to the point
that if these levels gets broken, we can
also go to stop in profit of€1,000.
>> Mhm.
>> Not 1,000, like 800.
and say if it goes bad we use this
profit to make another trade.
>> Gotcha.
>> Yeah.
>> But the major movement of the day we
took it in the first 20 minutes. That's
the major movement of the day. The break
then you can play it longterm.
>> Yeah.
>> And if you play longterm you have 1 to
10 risk-to-reward but you get a lower
win rate.
>> Of course.
>> Or you can just say give my cash
>> session is done.
>> Are you able in uh in futures as part of
this are you able to like partial your
trades?
>> Of course. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. Yes. So, is that something is that
something you sometimes do? Let's say in
this example, it's a good one to be
fair.
>> Uh would you for example, you had
multiple contracts on and you're in this
position. Would you say considering that
I go heavy and I go with multiple
contracts when I see this rejection, I
would already take out half of the
contracts
>> because I'm risk free. Okay.
>> Exactly. Yeah.
>> I can take profit and I can continue to
scale in if I want. Okay.
>> I don't like when the market gets weak.
So, I will take out here. But education
wise I want the trade to get completed.
Either we are stopped out at break even
either we go to take profit. I don't
want to
create additional difficulty of trade
management that this advance.
>> Yeah. Because even then with trade
management it's quite personal
>> part of the like it's a big part of the
>> but when it comes to say the high of
previous day
>> is that something then let's say you've
taken half off
>> would that be your next sort of target
or if let's say price goes to you know
one to three or four and then shows
similar where we're getting a bit of
weakness
>> you want to know everything
>> give me all the secrets
>> so the point is you when I told you I
will scale out it's exactly because when
you see this the step is aggressive
sellers. Yeah,
>> you you coded the algorithm.
>> Uh the next step is aggressive sellers.
Now, if aggressive sellers gets
recovered,
>> yeah,
>> this was funny.
>> If aggressive sellers gets recovered, we
should expect another explosion up the
second squeeze.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, let's go back to your
question. Um like
>> cuz bearing in mind, right, the each one
of these is 40. You set it to 40
contracts, right?
>> 40. But these big balls, maybe it's 100.
>> Exactly. That's what I was saying. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh these are big boys. Okay. So I would
like these big boys to be squeezed or to
get back to the low volume node.
>> Yeah.
>> So for example, we were at the high
there in real time or or you know, if we
weren't in this setting, you probably
would have taken half off. Yes. Let's
say price comes back to break even on
that trade, no problem. But then you're
going to look at the reaction from the
low volume node. Is it again a
confirmation based?
>> Of course. Like again, I if this one
goes to half profit and half break even,
I would use half the profit that I made
to wait for the trades there because I'm
pretty sure that if we get back to the
low volume node,
>> we get aggressive buyers, we are going
to run to the high. So you can
>> just bear in mind where did this get to?
It's got to about 800. You say €800?
>> Yeah, like 800. But I'll fit 400.
>> Exactly. But now it's easy for people at
home to maybe think, oh,
>> this is only one contract.
>> Exactly. Yeah. That's what I was going
to say. So like, you know, you make that
10 contracts for example. So you would
have taken 4,000.
>> 4,000 within a few minutes.
>> That's the point. The more the account
size, the more you feel confident to
>> get continuous profit for the day.
>> Yeah.
>> And then if you want to scale in, you
scale in with the profit. This is you
anticipated what I wanted to say to you
like
>> how I did this performance in the world
trading cup is building profit for the
day, building profit for the day,
building profit for the day and in
directional days I risk for example in
10 trades the profit that I made for the
day and you get a huge percentage
>> of course
>> but you are only risking profit of the
day.
>> Yeah.
>> If the day gets close this profit is
locked in it's equity. It's not more
profit. You cannot risk it.
>> So the next day reset
>> reset.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And if you think about
what's the concept of this, when the
model goes well, you take risk. Yeah.
Because the model is respecting what
you're saying. If the model goes back,
ready for the squeeze, huh? Ready for
the squeeze coming? Uh sellers
aggressive here. No follow through.
>> Yeah. So we need this eye. If this eye
gets broken, we go here.
>> Yeah.
>> Done. Uh what was I saying? That you
build your position with multiple scalps
and uh this means that when the market
condition is favorable to you, you make
a lot of money.
>> Yeah.
>> When the market condition is bad, you
take the first two or three stop loss
and you are out.
>> Done.
>> Yeah.
>> One trade the next day, everything
covered. I have a maximum stop- loss for
the day like in percentage term that is
2%. So when I say to people this day I
took eight stop loss I only lost 2%.
Exactly. That's what they don't
understand. They see the time maybe they
risking 3% per stop loss. Of course it's
a lot
>> but that's not how you deal with risk
management.
>> And what's important to highlight as
well as we were talking about contracts
and you know if you had more contracts
this would have been X amount. What's
important to highlight with that is that
that's not where you start right. You
start with the low. Yeah. Micro. you
build over time and and I think people
hear over time and they automatically
assume that's a long time but it's all
perception right so like if it takes you
two to three to four years to really
start to build a position size up and
your confidence and your skill
>> isn't that worth being able to make four
five $10,000 in a day right in a day yes
but then don't hear that line and think
oh yeah that's you that's incredible I
can do that ASAP and whatever it's the
three to five years of dedication and
and hard work and really intricate
detail that then allows you to have that
skill set. But it's like a lot of people
aren't willing to sacrifice and
understand that. And as I said, this is
a this is a a strategy and a playbook
that is truly for trade actual traders,
you know, not for people who like the
idea of trading, if that makes sense.
>> Yes, I totally agree with you. And also
like
I know it's easier to believe in the
fairy tales of the Metatrader
bot that makes money for you when you
sleep
>> or just the signal service that is able
to put money to put food on your table
when you don't do anything. But that's
not the reality. and uh message to the
audience. Trust only people that give
you some sort of verification or even
better live analysis. If you can live
trading, if you can track record and
understand if they are doing what they
are saying they do.
>> Yeah.
>> Because there is a big difference
between people that make money with the
market and people that make money
pretending to trade the market like with
service connected to them. In this case,
you see they revisit again the big
traits. Yeah. No follow through. Going
back to the now I remove a little bit
because I cannot really see price.
>> So let's remove it.
So the message I want to give to them
they he didn't take out us on break even
on the second position but we took out
position here half of the position. You
see how much this level it's important
and this level the market is using to
pivo. This is not a case. This is when
buyers decided
>> that it was too expensive to continue
buying.
>> So this is the cap of the auction. The
Mustang got too much expensive for us.
>> Yeah.
>> If they are changing their narrative
when we will see another candle, we can
continue to trail our stop in profit.
>> Like
>> it's not ringing the wheel. I will keep
this visual for now without big orders
because otherwise I cannot see where is
our break even. And here is our premium
setup. If we are willing to go back and
cover the low volume node, we will use
half of the profit that we made to um
strike up even with one contract. This
can be a $4,000 trades if we wait for
the eye.
>> Yeah.
>> But we need to stay here till evening
because I think the volatility I can see
it's it was big in the beginning but now
it's drying up.
>> So let's see. Let's see at least if we
reach the target without taking out the
other position at break even.
That other trade that we discussed in
terms of outside of your playbook and
some traders might have it in their
playbook.
>> Um and you said though with that trade
it makes sense to target the you know
the the ceiling that we had at the time.
Yes. Exactly.
>> Because you don't know if it's going to
break higher.
Would it be if someone was taking that
setup or would would that be a setup you
would take if you had already traded in
the day made some profits or even then
it would be because it's it's not a bad
setup. It's a good setup. Just
>> let's
>> would you take the full setup out here
or would it if in that case you had
multiple contracts? Is that another one
where you would say half off leave?
>> I do something really smart. Okay.
>> I take the setup out here but I'm ready
to open it back with the profit I made
if it breaks.
>> Okay. Okay. So, you're able to
>> I don't take the risk of indecision
here.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> I I bring the money in my account then
I'm willing to put the money on the
table.
>> Yeah.
>> If I have a confirmation
>> like it makes more sense. I tried what
you say to keep it.
>> Yeah.
>> But seven times it snap back. You get a
break and you say I should I I can
include it start the day at 3 hour
>> and I let the market take out everything
is preparing the squeeze.
>> Yeah. So all those red orders here are
right now under water. We take that
high. We should squeeze up.
>> You're getting good.
>> Teacher being prepared.
>> We have a great
>> What can we expect?
>> Buyer said the eye.
>> Yeah.
>> The auction got expensive now. More
expensive. They are willing to pay
higher price for it. So absorbed.
Absorbed.
You can put in stop in profit if you
want. I will not do it because the test
here it's really probable to happen.
>> Yeah.
>> But we took a really exponential move.
You see almost zero draw down like from
when we entered there was zero to non
draw down like we enter in this candle
it continue again seller trying to step
in in a parabolic move
>> in this particular here. Now is this now
the level we would hope would hold?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> This if you want to be conservative the
>> down there. Yeah. down there because
this is the protection level of the
sellers. Why we saw this exponential
move even someone will think we are
expensive. Why? Because these sellers
are closing position and this
>> creating even more momentum.
Now again same situation sellers
aggressive buyers that needs to decide
if they want to protect this level and
continue to be aggressive here.
>> Mhm.
>> Now we are reaching 22
round number.
>> Yes,
>> this is a really important number.
>> Price will accumulate or distribute
around this level. So you can also
decide to if it breaks this high
with aggression, you can also take the
second position with a really tight stop
loss. So if it goes bad, you take
another $600 or $700, but at least you
are protecting yourself. So if we tap
this eye, the stop loss goes here.
>> Yeah. So our stop loss
>> our stop loss goes here. So we make more
than the first position, but still we
are protected.
>> Yes.
And then someone can say what if it goes
if it test and then goes up. Okay, we
are protected on the second one. It's
another 7 $700 here because if this eye
doesn't hold and the market collapse, I
don't want to give back to the market
all the profit that we made. We made an
amazing zero draw down entry here
>> because this is in consideration that
that's our target. So then the it's a
negative risk-to-reward to allow us to
go back.
>> Exactly. Exactly. I'm not willing to
give to the market all this money back.
>> Yeah. and see our sellers are starting
to participate on the top, I don't like
it. I expect a a squeeze that will bring
us to target. But if is this level gets
broken, I I I have too much profit to
give back. It's not worth for me.
>> Mhm.
>> So our stop loss now it's I will show
you this low.
>> Okay.
>> And I can see that it's not easy to
break this high because you have to
consider that it's around number. Buyers
are getting aggressive again buying the
top.
If this auction fail, I think we will
revisit the low low volume node
>> all the way. Yeah.
>> Yeah. All the way. So we can have
another position with made 400 on the
first, 700 or 600 on the second. We are
floating on out. Yeah. Totally out on
the position.
Let's remove everything.
It's important to highlight as well. So
at this point maybe roughly $1,000
$1,100 um in ter in total profits.
>> Yeah.
>> And bear in mind because I think social
media causes a a slight problem in the
trading space where they think $1,100 is
not a lot of money. Bear in mind
that's,100 in roughly about half an hour
>> with one contract.
>> With one contract. But not even just
that though.
>> Even $1,100 in a single day
>> Mhm. is incredible because if you're
trading for a month and on average you
whatever 50% win rate whatever it may be
you're still coming out with a very good
yearly salary in a month almost.
>> Yes.
>> Right.
>> And that's incredible and that's like
position number one. That's like as you
scale in your trading journey that's how
it should look. Now, I know it's so easy
with social media to assume you need to
be making a $100,000 a month every
single month or multiple hundreds of
thousands. And that is possible, right?
And there are traders doing that, but
they didn't start that way. They go
through the process step by step.
>> Look at the precision of the reversal
point. We saved all this money
>> that the market want to give to get back
>> like from here. This is I want to show
you something and I will make another
prediction that is not a trade. Okay.
>> But is this where the market will
reverse
>> this delta from
here to here it's not worth the trade.
>> Yeah.
>> Because here it's full of big trades not
having a follow-up. I expect that from
here we get all the way back from here.
>> Mhm.
>> And we can use this two $500 trades to
make another one to three. Now
>> let's say if we take another two trades
for the day. One to three. $500 series,
it's another $3,000 only using the
profit.
>> Worst case scenario, we close break even
of the day. Yeah.
>> Like the reason traders are unprofitable
is they try to get the home run. So
maybe they get this breakout and they
all till the top without taking partial
without you can never go broke by taking
partial like you you are sitting on
profit for the day.
>> And in this case as well like there's
nothing in between that you would look
for. You would only wait for price to
come back to that higher probable area.
Let's see. I will exactly tell you where
I expect a reaction considering that
still the momentum by I didn't saw the
big picture, but the momentum buy is
amazing.
But
let's get the the whole picture.
>> It's incredible though because it shows
you when you're dissecting price when
you're logged in.
>> I I lose the conception of time really.
I I was thinking that it was 20 minutes
that we were there.
>> It did feel to be fair to you. It did
feel like that. Yeah,
>> this is a huge volume. Huge
low volume note.
>> Yeah, you can see
>> like it's a squeeze. It's very
>> So I will not engage in other trades
here. Just the first trade that I would
watch is here. But watching the
momentum, I don't think uh we will go
back. So you can just continue to adapt
to the position using the profit.
>> If you want, we can continue to see it.
Can one minute and see what big boys are
doing.
So my take and this is against the
probability is that this is a wall.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So this is the trade that you
never need to do. But if I need to
consider a trade,
this is what I'm afraid about. Okay.
>> Of that happen.
>> This is the reason I took out the buy
position before.
>> Gotcha. Round number. Seller getting
aggressive. Buyers not having a follow
through. Was there any of this slowdown
as well? Was that take that into account
as well?
>> Yes, because this one it's compression
again. Okay.
>> The market getting back inside
compression. Usually it's a visit of the
low.
>> Okay.
>> Uh now let's see what cumulative volume
delta is saying. This is an important
information that we are putting in for
the first time here.
>> Mhm. And this
the cumulative volume pressure of the
market
visualizing candlestick. You see that
it's short
>> down here. Yeah,
>> this is an information because the
squids was supported
but then we started to distribute.
>> Yes.
>> Again all this by movement no follow up.
>> Yeah. Divergence. M this divergence is
significant because it means that there
is something big here. So two scenario
either it breaks and we take another
continuation trades that is amazing for
us
but I know this asset and I think that
we are going to revisit from here either
this low or this low volume then we take
even better trades. Yeah,
>> this is a pattern that I have seen a lot
of times. Four consecutive weeks every
week taking out the high but not
creating new value.
>> If there is a big buy trades here a
collapses is soon. Of course, it's not a
trade because we are counter trend on
it.
Let's see if the doesn't get old. I'll
tell you that it doesn't go.
Yes. Yes. It's this one. Big trades, no
follow through. Yeah.
>> Sellers building the narrative.
Cumulative volume delta going down. Here
we go.
>> Would you say uh do you only trade
NASDAQ and Q?
>> NASDAQ because uh it's a lot of
information to deal with.
>> Yeah.
>> I tried one time with NASDAQ and crude
oil, but I was a therapist. I need DP
psychologist at the end of the uh
>> but would you say that also though even
though yes it's a lot of information by
really tuning into one asset such as NQ
>> yeah it's the the cheat code like
understand
>> like you just said I've seen I know this
pair
>> this was feeling like this one is the
intuition part
>> it's a counter trend trades I will never
take it but we took from the bottom to
the eye and we exit at the top
>> we saved the delta profit that was here
that if I was using my ego I will say
No, we go to target.
>> Yeah,
>> because this is my target. But this
capacity to adapt to market behavior
here in this amount of error, we took an
explosion that is five times more. It's
not easy to time the market in this way.
If these big trades protect and break
the high, we have another buy.
>> Mhm.
>> So, we can again jump on the train. And
the problem with if you're trying to say
long and then short is that the real
bias is still long. But let's say if
this comes up now and and you get break
even or stop loss.
>> A lot of people's psychology
is that they will still focus on the
short cuz that's the one they lost.
>> Yes.
>> Instead of realizing where the original
bias is by taking this lowquality setup
that yeah okay might be might pull
through might be able to make some good
profit from whatever it may be. The
problem is our mindsets get fixed on
that bias then and that happens to a lot
of people. I think a lot of people let's
say coming into this session as a good
example coming into this session they
did the same market analysis you did
long bias
>> price shot down they switch to short
they take a loss.
>> Yes.
>> But then the problem is they don't
switch back or recognize their mistake
and they stick on the loss and they
stick on the short and they keep trying
to short all the way up. They marry
their trades
>> and then they end up in, you know,
blowing their challenge, blowing their
account, taking a heavier loss than
they're meant to when in reality they
had to, you know, you've done your, it's
like you said earlier, right? When
you're at war, you don't make the
changes, right?
>> You don't make change when you are
fighting. Yeah. Like the changes are
made in the tent with generals and
planning the war
up front.
>> Mhm.
>> In this case, it's building a goodby
setup.
>> Yeah.
Huge amount of buy here.
Watching the narrative here. I don't
think we will retrace back. Look where
it tapped in. Low volume node. Now what
we need to be back in the trade? We need
a breakout of this high.
>> Yeah.
>> So the next set uh buy stop.
>> Uh no, I want a full candle close.
>> Okay.
>> On this one. So risky.
>> What's the reason for that one? Because
we're already quite high.
>> Because the bias is clear. The bias is
clear. The target is still not taken.
The momentum is big and the interesting
is big. Like this candle, this um uh big
order is bigger than all this area.
>> Okay,
>> these traders are getting squeezed. So
if we break this high, we test this
area. I will target for
another $12,000
trade
getting to
22062.
This will be the trade.
But you see how much fast you need to
put your ego aside and say this was the
narrative that I was building. It didn't
break the high but it broke the low.
Yeah. So it can be still a retracement
to the low volume node. What I need the
trade is valid as soon as we close with
a one minute candle full body candle
>> above this
>> where we were failing.
>> Yeah, where we were failing.
>> Even better if in the move up there is a
big trade cell that gets destroyed like
here.
Let's see.
And how long have you been trading this
way?
>> This way it's around four years that I
use order flow more than price action.
Before I started before four years I
started to get only the trigger from
order flow. Now I'm full order flow like
I use price action only as a proxy and a
result of volume. Yeah. like I you you
see I always compare the volume with the
result that is providing and um but the
learning curve is still like 20% of what
you can understand with this. So I still
am one
>> 20% of the real power of order flow I
mastered like I still need to to get
better sometimes because I think there
>> especially nowadays with machine
learning and neural network you can put
this kind of data in an algorithm that
really helps you to remove all the
noise. Mhm.
>> And um I think in the area of artificial
intelligence, understanding deeply this
data and using AI to just get a better
um risk management or position
management, journaling all your trades.
>> This is an idea for Omar. Like using
artificial intelligence for the journal
is something that can really step up the
game a lot. And
>> it's incredible how much when you have
2,500 sample also a small change in risk
management change the curve of the
equity line. Yeah.
>> Like you can go parabolic or you can go
stable or you can go like this small
change. So the strategy it's 30%.
Let's say 33%. 33% is the mindset the
trader that is behind and that it can
stay calm when it's not
>> his setup or playbook presenting. Yeah.
The other trend 33% is the risk
management part. Definitely it's a huge
part.
>> Definitely. Yeah, that's something that
um I did a round table with uh you know
verified seven and eight figure traders
Zuma was there as well and that was one
thing that seemed to stand out is that
once traders had gotten the strategy
down
>> right had their playbook and then they
have the psychology at this point they
have consistency
>> a huge portion of that change in P&L
>> is tweaking the risk management by
really mastering and focusing on that
>> totally.
So what are you seeing here then? So at
this stage obviously we've seen this big
buyer.
>> We are we are still in a uh buy
narrative.
>> Is that that setup that you have mapped
out there still valid?
>> The the sell
>> the the buy sorry
>> the buy is still valid. Yes. Totally.
>> And uh it's still not activated because
they need to break the
>> Exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
>> But is is valid. The nar the narrative
is valid. I was interested in this buy.
If it gets bro bro bro bro bro bro bro
bro bro bro bro bro bro bro bro bro bro
bro bro bro broken and tested we will
keep this narrative. Yeah
>> but still we are long. We broke the high
of the consolidation. So we are in the
expansion phase that we explained before
>> at this stage where we are now. Anyway,
I know obviously it's still valid
anyway. But if I say you saw some
sellers try to step in and they get
absorbed just add to the confidence. If
I see sellers getting absorbed here, it
would be amazing
>> because it says look we are also heavy
on limit order not only aggressive
orders because these are execution but
if you see a sell aggressive not getting
a follow through it means that the
buyers are also protecting from limit
order absorbing. So you have two forces
pushing in the same direction and it's a
really good trades.
>> Yeah,
>> I'm really optimistic on this one. like
>> it's a long way to go up here, but still
we are in the dealing range that we want
to trade because we still didn't took
out the
>> previous day
>> previous daily high. Yeah.
>> And would you say as well this
compression we're seeing at this high,
if we were to break higher, it would
essentially be another squeeze. So
because of that range that we've kind of
been building here at the high, if we
were to break higher,
>> it would be all the these sellers and
these sellers here
>> Mhm.
>> would have to close and there's I think
there's one in there as well.
>> Yeah. Yeah, but then they would
essentially have to close out which
would then cause us to push towards
target more.
>> They will uh get an exponential move of
the price here. I'm pretty sure about
it.
>> But we need to give them a reason to
close the trades because still now they
can be right.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> They are going to be proven wrong if we
first break this level. But if we
approach this ice before so I don't want
to lose the trade because if I wait here
to step in Yeah. I risk that it's
another explosion like this and we are
unfilled.
>> Yes.
>> So I will just take a level because when
we break this one the probability that
we will continue high. So our margin of
error is small because we are only
losing $595. This is half of the profit
that we already made.
>> Yes.
>> But if it goes good we add another
1,200. So we are sitting on the day for
$2,200.
>> Just to confirm for everyone, we're not
in this trade yet.
>> Yeah. No, no, no. Uh when you see this
level here, it's long one contract and
>> price takes that low.
>> Mhm. Does that you
>> invalid invalid because it means that
the seller these buyers are not
aggressive enough to push it up. But can
I show you something I need to remove
because the narrative that I have is
really clear on the long and I will
explain you why.
Let's consider all this compression
here. Now let's take into account all
this area. Okay. Yeah,
>> we are not willing to break
the
>> right
>> the value area low.
>> Mhm.
>> But we are willing to sit
>> above the P.
>> Yeah.
>> If we are sitting above the P
consistently, it means that it's an
accumulation.
>> Yeah.
>> Not always, but statistically wise, it's
more probable that we will approach this
high.
>> Yeah. And if we approach this eye and we
spike up, these traders are forced to
close their position. If they are forced
to close the position, we experience
another catalyst in price that gives us
the possibility to to be break even in
one minute because we enter here, it
approach here, it explode here, break
even.
>> So it's only temporary the $600 loss.
Now I want to I want to see if
approaching here we have aggressive
sellers not willing to
um not willing to have a reaction like
pushing but
>> limit order are absorbing them. Let's
see how is it going. I want to activate
also because it's really useful the
commumulative volume delta in this
situation.
So what the cumulative volume delta is
saying now is that they are building
momentum down. So we can expect what is
called a whipsaw.
>> Okay.
>> Take off the law.
But as you can see also here
consolidation like also here like
replicating the same scenario.
>> Mhm.
>> In this situation here.
Let's see.
They say that scalpers don't have
patience but a lot. It's not it's not
like swing but it's a lot of patient to
wait for the correct setup.
>> Exactly. Yeah, that's true.
>> So
I will only use these two signal
the value area low and I will use the
same color blue
and the value area high
that is this one.
Okay, then
I will cancel this one. There's a little
bit of delay for connection I think.
And um what we will do is we will
observe when we approach this level, if
we approach this level, the behavior of
the big trades
still not participating.
>> Mhm.
>> Still bias control.
>> Does this just mean uh
>> No, no, it's live. It's live. just uh I
think let me reload but I think it works
properly. Let's see if there is any
change.
No, it works. Let me check with the
phone
if there is any discrepancy in price
but I think no.
Oh no, it disappeared. It was only
temporary.
There was delay 5 seconds, 10 seconds
the red the mark, but
we are approaching the high
still buyers controlling like if we want
to get the horizontal level is exactly
the one protecting this order. So my
stop loss is a little bit too generous.
should be like this to be honest.
>> Mhm.
>> Exactly $500.
>> This uh price consolidating the way it
is right now. Is that would you say
that's a positive thing, negative thing
or just neutral?
>> It's positive thing because it's most
probably a reaccumulation before because
the market cannot look here. It's
skyrocket up.
>> Yep.
>> Without retracing. This is not um
efficient market exchange. This is
inefficiency price action.
>> So this one is necessary if we want to
reach the top of the day. This one is
the market cannot be parabolic.
>> Yeah.
>> Because there needs to be interaction
like sellers trying to step in. And now
if we analyze sellers trapped, buyers
aggressive,
big node on the top, possible squeeze.
>> If we break this one, this one are
forced to close.
>> Mhm.
It's a good setup. This one is a good
setup. And the good part is that we are
using profit of the profit. This is
psychologically also really
convenient for us.
>> So you have a 2% limit on loss
>> loss for the day. On the worst case
scenario, I lose 2%. That is
eight trades.
>> Yeah.
>> But doesn't happen often can happen one
time every two months.
>> Yeah. So in in in this case though like
if you were trading at your own desk
right now
>> and um so first trade's a a win are you
taking trades like this trade another
trade for example would you be taking
any of those other trades that we
discussed uh as well or trying them or
is I will take the exact same trade if
it was on desk the only difference is
that I'm with a trackp now and I have a
mouse that have shortcut so I can just
execute faster and also put at break
even with one shortcut like the
execution it's really important like
with a laptop it's not the best to do
scalping
>> but uh yes these are two valid setup the
setup that we took before is exactly
what I would execute in the water in cup
if I was still participating in it we
are approaching the high and um
exactly at the level I told you
>> so now participating we are waiting for
full candle because it can be a fake out
on the full candle we are in it's one
minute chart so it's really easy
>> see if you we were in before we would
risk the whip saw
>> now what happens if the full candle
arrives here we cannot have this big
stop loss so we will just cover ourself
below the big trade okay
>> got
>> so let's see how it goes
we are still not in.
So I need to adapt my stop loss.
If the candle close even here, we are
still risking even less 355. But I need
to see that it close above this box.
>> Yes.
>> If it close inside, I'm not engaging.
>> If it closes inside then closes above
the box, you're in or it close below.
Yeah.
>> So, not in.
>> Okay. But if it now closed above,
>> you see why not?
>> Yeah.
>> If it now closed above, I still can
consider the trade. But, uh, I need to
cover myself below this bias. Yes.
This is potential area accumulation. So,
I can have a really small stop loss.
It's this trade execute. I will
participate here. It's $275
loss.
>> Okay.
>> 20% of what we got for the day.
>> So, are you doing that because that is,
you know, if we go below that low, the
setup is essentially fine anymore.
>> Okay. So, it doesn't matter about, oh,
you have $600 worth of risk you could
use. So, give it wider.
>> I'm showing one contract, but if the
risk is only $280,
I can scaling contract like I can bring
the risk to $500. So, two contracts in
this case.
>> I got you. Yes. Okay. I understand.
Yeah. Let's see. Okay, we are in here.
Close of the candle. We are in. We are
risking $260 to make potential
1,100.
It's one to five. One
>> to five and a halfish. Yeah.
>> Five and a half. The good part is that
when we approach this,
>> if we break, we are risk free
immediately.
>> If we break that,
>> yeah, we break this one, you see the
catalyst.
>> Okay.
>> We go risk free.
>> Got you. and like some seconds and we go
risk free.
>> So now you'd be risk free.
>> Yes, the risk is free. It's
it can be below this aggression candle
but it's still risky. I will still not
go risk-f free because I think we will
test this level. I will take the risk to
take a loss on this one. Yeah,
>> you can go risk free when you see candle
accepting the high.
>> Yeah,
>> this one is still not accepting the high
and the risk is that it test then
skyrocket up and you are out of your
position
>> and it moves too fast.
>> No, it's again test. You see what I
saved
>> does the upper
top of the range.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> I saved the fact that I will get
liquidated if I go too fast risk free.
And you can say you can re-enter. Yes,
but what if now it explode?
>> It's too fast.
>> Yes, it's too fast. Now, when we get a
full money candle up, Yeah. we can get
risk-free.
>> Okay.
>> You're getting anxious.
>> Yeah, we're dry. We're getting We're
getting good by the end of this be a
whole different trader. That's it.
But be honest, is it more clear than
price action or
>> Yeah, it is. It is. Uh it's way more
clear. Like I said, the one of the most
clearest orderflow breakdowns we've done
so far, for sure. And to be able to do
it live as well and see it live is
incredible. Um, and I'll tell you that,
you know, the platform's been incredible
as well because, as I said, previous
ones I've seen, it's it feels very
overwhelming as someone who doesn't use
orderflow,
>> while this one you can incorporate a lot
of this information quite cleanly,
especially like you had the volume
profile with the delta, and then you
have uh, you know, the orders being
shown as well, the large orders being
shown,
>> and it all feels quite clean. And the
the beauty is you can just click a
button, hide them off, put them back on.
>> Yeah.
So you see it's not it's a fail this is
a failed deduction like every time it
approach the high and get back our
probability that we will get a stop loss
gets higher.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> So if we approach again and it gives me
the ability to put my stop loss to break
even here I will do because the setup is
getting the more time the the weaker the
weaker the weaker a good setup create an
explosion here.
>> Okay. So yes, there are these big orders
protecting, but the probability that it
will just spike out and liquidate me is
getting higher and higher.
And that's exactly what happened. So how
much we lost on this one? $255.
So the ability to be able to spot this
here saves you to put a stop loss like
the beginning we wanted to do here
>> down here. Yeah.
>> No, it's a half the risk. Let's adopt
the the narrative. We are in profit of
750 for the day because we lost two $250
on this one. What can we do? If this big
order gets again absorbed, we can
engaged. But we need to see again
aggression of the market participants.
We can take a final position of other
$500 to target for either the eye of the
day either one to two one to three
riskto-reward.
What happened here? Why we have this
movement? Aggressive buyers no follow
through.
>> Mhm.
>> Getting back in sellers locking the
movement.
Now either we go here either the buyers
take control. From what I'm seeing, we
go here. Why aggressive buyers? No
followup.
>> Yep.
>> Like
if you want this can be a short but it's
against the
>> the bias.
>> The bias. So we will not experience it
and we will not try it. So we are
waiting that the market gives us a new
long position.
>> Mhm.
>> That of course is not providing at the
moment.
So would you need to uh see price close
back above any certain level before
looking to X?
>> Yes, I will show you also which level.
Now
the consolidation era is still the same.
Okay, let's remove for a second the big
trades
and let's go on what really matters.
Did it break the value area low? No. Did
it break the value area high? Yes. Okay.
First information. Now sellers are
getting really aggressive here. What
does it mean? Like before before
skyrocketing the market up, it took the
low.
Okay. So either this candle is full of
aggressive sellers. There is a big ball
here. Either we go back here and I see
market activity participant buy and I
engage. Either we use the trend
following setup only when it closed the
candle here. You remember break testing
here like we did here. This explosion
was taken thanks to this. Okay. So we
took a stop loss here. We don't want to
engage in the noise now.
>> Yeah. Just want to be patient about it.
Let's see what
>> cuz otherwise let's say you know we get
involved now. we could easily continue
lower or even if we even if we close
above this uh the top of the range there
could still go lower while if we break
above
>> then we could have a high
>> prob low probability that you will go
lower and also consider that if it
breaks higher you have a really clear
level where to cover yourself. So you
either you are right, either you are
wrong really really fast here you can
try along here get stopped out try again
here get stopped out here if it breaks
and it comes back is not valid anymore.
Yeah you cannot get stopped out for no
reason.
>> So this could you going back to your
analogy as well about you know during
the battle this is essentially like
during the battle here where we entered
the trade that we just got stopped out
on was when we had exited the battle.
>> Mhm.
>> Then it ended up being a loss. That's
fine.
>> Yes. It's part of trading,
>> but now we're in the battle again. So,
we're not looking to make a decision
now.
>> No,
>> we want to come away from it.
>> Exactly.
>> But it's planned ahead of time.
>> Yes.
>> Now, at the moment, sellers are willing
this battle. If sellers are willing to
win this battle, this one needs to
close. If this one needs to close, then
we'll squeeze down. Uh we will do the
opposite. We'll squeeze down. See
aggressive sellers here jumping back
liquidating all these ones and from here
we can get the big buy movement of the
day.
>> Yeah,
>> let's see how it behaves. Still didn't
took the low. The squeeze happens when
you took the low here and they have one,
two, three, four, five low to revisit.
Let's see how they will behave.
>> Would you say usually What time are we
into the open? We're couple hours in.
Yes. Couple hours in the open.
>> At this stage normally is there more
volatility would you say or is this
>> not like it's you see compression day
first movement we made profit. Yeah.
>> Then we lost in compression. As I told
you the model don't work properly when
there is compression.
>> Mhm.
>> Why we are still in profit if we took
one take profit and one loss for only
one reason our risk management. Yeah.
>> We took profit when is necessary. We are
wrong. When we are wrong we are wrong
immediately. You see the squeeze like
took the first low accelerated to the
second. If accelerate to the second, it
accelerate to the third. Big
liquidation, fill the low volume node.
Market makers don't like when the
exchange is not um transaction properly.
They don't like to void here. Okay.
>> So you can see them from the low volume
uh node and usually they get filled. So
this cell if we were ignoring all of
this this cell is saying sellers are
getting aggressive but they are not
having a follow through.
>> Yeah.
>> But in this situation we are also having
a fail auction. If here we have a
breakout of the candle and we get back
here this could be a trade.
>> Yeah.
>> Is not the situation because also the
buyers are not willing. So we are in the
situation if you remember of the London
session that we saw not clear direction
not clear breakout long-term bias is
clear is long
>> but not a good setup to to take.
>> Yeah
>> let's remove the big trades here.
Let's watch what's happen. So they took
the first two loss, they get back inside
in the sellers are still aggressive
here. We didn't reach the value area low
and we failed the auction here. Now
let's clean everything.
If we clean everything, we see something
really clear
this failed option. But at the same
time, and I need to go on five minutes
to show you this,
the bias is clear. But look at this this
situation.
They didn't even revisit from the first
trade that we took the balance area.
So what can we do now?
We can
use the full impulse
to time
the delta
and what we see we go deep inside
the by delta that is more relevant is
concentrated here in this three point
one two and three these are the biggest
one even if it's a void and this
coherent with the test of this now if we
get back here we have aggressive buyers
we have sellers that are in deep loss
yeah that can close the position and
skyrocket up so from this situation I
expect that shortterm the bias is still
long we can accelerate and this exactly
what we are doing so now it's time to
take some of those previous lows that
you mentioned we are going to take them.
It's
not worthy to take a long here against
the momentum. Yeah,
the narrative is really clear. The
squeeze is happening. They took the
first three low. They are going to
target this other one. When they do it,
they rebalance the low volume node. When
they rebalance the low volume node, we
have our opportunity to take a $500
trade. Yeah. To 2,000 profit, 3,000
profit for the day.
And we are done.
Let's see. Now we can put now that it's
moving.
You see really aggressive accelerating
to our
>> accepted.
Now I will never dream about putting the
buy here without seeing some absorption
or some aggressive buyers stepping in.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I will before wait this one is a
continuation model like sellers
aggressive buyers trying
>> you want them to fail.
>> You want them to like it's accelerating
still pushing low.
when it's uh yellow it's irrelevant like
it's not relevant volume
>> okay
>> so it's below the threshold okay
>> then uh you can point it out I think we
are going to yes we are going to push it
out till this
>> Mhm.
If these traders close the position,
skyrocket up, we are experience the
first time that we are seeing this now.
>> Yeah.
>> What risks can can we take here? If
let me show you this is the candle that
incorporated all this sell volume
inside. If they manage to break the high
of this candle, okay, and get back in,
not even if I calculated on purpose,
$500 risk,
we can shoot up
to $2,000 trade. It's a one to four
riskto-reward.
We will see later if it is still what we
need to have to activate this setup
break out with full body candle of this
high.
>> Okay. So you need to close.
>> I need to close. Yes. So
>> if the market goes down great aggressive
cell I recalibrate my stop loss.
>> Okay.
>> Let's see what it does.
Still I expect a whipso down. Why
the buyers follow through is garbage.
>> Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Um the sellers Yes. The sellers can push
out up closing this position but the
reaction of the buyers is not so good.
>> If we start to go above here the sellers
will be forced to close. This can be a
catalyst for up. But I would like to see
that we reach this global node. This is
really interesting.
Let's see if we manage to get it.
>> Just so you know, you hold the record
for the longest char episode.
>> Really?
>> That's right.
>> Probably approaching four or five hours,
I think, by now.
>> Really? It's a course. It's not a
>> Yeah, exactly. Exactly.
>> We told the people free education, you
know, that you've never seen before.
And, you know, we like to deliver and
you've helped us to do that. Like I
said, I'm excited to see the feedback,
the comments from everyone.
>> Interesting. Interesting.
Ultra aggressive sellers getting
absorbed
close to the low volume node. So this
trade is not valid.
Okay, we are canceling it.
Now this low volume node is created by
this candle.
>> Mhm.
>> And they try to create a new low but it
failed to do it. So we expect that if we
approach again this low we have the
final drive
>> when the bubbles present themselves on
the chart is that when the
>> execution has taken yes okay
>> exactly
>> so you expect so especially for that
size
>> you would expect price when it's
happened to to instantly move really so
the fact it doesn't is where we're
saying absorption
>> yes exactly
>> because if we look back here for example
those buys came in we moved Yes. Yeah.
>> Same here. The sells came in, we didn't
move, but the buys came in. We Yes.
>> They they are
>> facilitated in moving the
>> the market. We are
>> What about now? What is your
>> We are getting ready for I need only the
lock in of uh
uh green. Here
we are approaching the level. So, I'm
waiting. You still need that closer.
>> Yes. This is exactly $500.
Let's put for now at 1,000. Let's see
the close.
The close is there.
Not yet. It's a one minute candle. You
needed to close above.
>> Yeah, it can close also below this one.
If it close the important is that it
close below this, above this and above
this.
>> So, still not doing it.
>> You see it's rejecting.
>> Okay.
>> This one is not okay. Still not in the
trade.
>> Gotcha.
Thanks God. Still not in the trade
because
as soon as the sellers are not are still
protecting the position, you will see
the retracement.
>> How often do you see like early buyers
early sellers as in traps essentially or
like okay getting in buyers early here
for example.
>> Mhm.
>> But then we go to that low volume.
>> Yeah. A lot of times does that happen a
lot? Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> That's why that confirmation is so
important.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it's like a semaphore like
if it's red and you are trying to pass
two times out of 10 it's working but the
other time you are crashing another car
like
>> now it's again presenting the setups
>> but you needed to close
>> I need to close but I think we are
>> almost there
let's see
>> yes closed okay we are in
just tested
So, we got filled.
Now, we can decide to scale one to two.
Yeah. At 1,00 and then scale the final
position out of the top of the day. If
we take a stop loss on this one, we will
close the day because the model is not
responding properly because we are in
consolidation phase. You see, we are
whipsome whips. So, we protect the
profit that we made for the day.
>> Yeah. Now I like these setups because
they are usually zero draw down like we
are getting the whips. So up we are
loaded here.
>> When can we put this position to break
even? Break this high we are risk free.
>> Yeah
let's see how it goes.
You notice something about the really
good setups that they go immediately in
profit. That's the reason this one I
decided to close only with $250 loss
because if it fail to option I you are
going to stop loss. There is no way you
will win a trade like this.
So we are in line with bias. We have
aggressive sellers stopped absorbed
not tapping directly on the low volume
node but on the same level where the
sellers get get absorbed before. Yeah,
bias is there.
Let's see if they reach at least the
close. No, because it was over
overlapped with this one.
Imagine now they spike down. Close this
one and stop this.
>> That happens, right?
>> Yeah, this will not surprise me. NASDAQ
a lot of time does
double legs with multiple spikes before
jumping. But the good part about NASDAQ
that now is not a good day. like we are
managing to make profit but this is the
worst day that you can have because
usually when it's building momentum is
trend falling this one is breakout we
saw break out
>> if we if we weren't in this saying right
now where we're trying to obviously
trade live and and continue to trade
>> if you were at home and you took that
first trade and you see this would you
then okay it's a day for me or would you
say
>> when I see that this model fails goes
back and I take profit from this
probably I will just take another
thousand profit and close for the day
because it's not the market environment
that is making me money.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I want to go more aggressive when
it's like long session was really nice.
You see uh directional move a lot of
volatility in explosion like fast one to
three setups now is getting like also
for price action trader is getting
really compressed.
>> Yeah. like all this area is not making
anything just breaking going down
breaking going down. So now we have two
scenario either we get another 1,000
profit and we close at 1,750
>> or we just get at least to break even
this one when we break this high and we
let it run.
>> Yeah. If you let it run
each contract that we open on this one
>> Mhm.
would give us. Let's go to the top of
the day.
For each contract we are making 3,680.
So sometimes it's worth it to do it
because if you get three or four
contract you can make five figures per
day.
>> Yeah.
>> But the win rate gets uh lower. So you
can have these amazing days if you are
heavy on the lot size like me. I I can
open five, six, seven, 10 uh of mini
contract. It's heavy. If you get 10
contract there, you can make $40,000. Uh
but the win rate drops drops down. I
This is just a personal like decision. I
prefer a lot of days of 3,000 5,000
6,000 2,000 5,000 8,000 and to build the
five to six figures for the month than
having 40,000 minus 3 - 5 - 4 - 3 is not
psychologically is not um helping me you
know and I think it's only ego because
you can just take for example let's say
that you are
>> sometimes what happens is it always
balance sometimes it balances Anyway,
yeah, but one person hasn't had to take
so many losses.
>> Yeah.
>> Which is, as you say, psychologically,
most people couldn't handle that. There
are going to be those occasional
psychopaths who can handle handle in the
beginning. Then I had one day where I
was floating 28,000 for the day. I
decided to keep for the eye.
>> It just reversed five tick below the eye
and I lost everything plus a stop loss
on the next trades.
>> So just I say, "No, it's just stupid.
just you can close at 28,000 you are
done for the week what you need to do
>> so it's heavier from the psychology side
>> it's
I will say also less profitable but I I
don't know because I never try to keep
my position open but for example today
you will be already in true loss if you
keep the stop loss there you don't trail
or you don't manage we would already
taken three loss
>> mhm
>> we will not be sitting on a profit now
soon we go to break even on this one
because it's going really good. We we
got inside here on the test.
>> When we reach the high, are you
expecting a squeeze
>> with this three? Yes. Okay.
>> That's the reason that I I say I will
bring to break even not close full
position here because with the right
squeeze it can go really fast to for
example 2,000. Okay. Can go really fast.
So let's take as a reference that we
bring to break even here. But what we
can expect is momentum. Now building for
the day
>> and when does your typically your
session come to an end?
>> It depends like uh some session consider
that I'm living in uh United Arab
Emirates. So I'm uh for me New York
session is uh really late. Yeah,
>> it's already uh 7.
>> Yeah,
>> 7 and um usually I finish 8 9 sometimes
10.
And it's not just convenient to keep. So
I do the first three to four hours of
the session.
>> Yeah.
>> And I just manage trades but I don't
decide not to take other trades. Now we
have um an opportunity to put our stop
loss to break even already. If this
break again this eye not to break even
to stop no to break even to break even.
If this eye breaks what the market is
saying to us is that aggressive buyers
are pushing sellers are trying to get
aggressive. but they are getting failed.
You know, I will not even say to break
even, but I will secure other $250. So,
putting stopping profit. So, in the
worst case scenario, we close $1,000 and
I'm still okay with it, you know.
Let's see if it approached the high and
get as Yes.
So, yes, exactly $250 for the day. Um,
that brings back back like if we didn't
took the previous loss.
>> Yeah. And uh you see building slowly the
profit for the day is not heavy mentally
and is not giving us the risk that if
now this is a failed auction that it
explode lower we get another $500 loss.
>> Yeah.
>> Like getting consistent wins getting all
your trading journal green it's better
than getting green on one day and red on
all the other days.
What happens if uh is that what you
would expect though if price was to come
to this level to go continue lower down
to here?
>> Considering that it's not breaking if it
goes back here and it breaks. Yes. It
will go at least to break even.
>> Yeah.
>> To to the previous level where we
entered.
>> So then you might as well put it into
profit.
>> Better be out. Better be out. like
securing uh securing some profit for the
day and uh
be able to make 1,000 in the worst
market environment. Secure for you five
or 10,000 when the condition are good.
>> Yeah.
>> Like look at this market.
>> The only trending environment that we
did is this one and we monetized it.
Exactly.
>> All the rest is just managing your risk
management and surviving this market
condition.
I decided to put that stopping profit
here because this failed option. Yeah.
Says a lot about what the price want to
do.
>> Okay.
>> Says a lot. So if we break this one, we
will collapse down and then you can say
maybe we react here. Yes. We can try
another trade but sitting on a profit.
>> Yeah.
>> Like we can risk the profit. Yeah.
>> And if it does come down though to the
low volume node for example, then you
have
>> then you you can use half of the 1,000
that we make.
>> Yeah. for uh for for it but just I know
NASDAQ and I know that after the huge
gap that it made usually the day is
rebalance you know because the yeah it's
it's a really not clear situation about
Iran and they are just compressing you
see also the buyers are not getting any
followup
>> like they are trying to push in the
market high but it was getting really
aggressive by the sellers we are still
not out of the position
Let's see if this buyer can protect it.
Consider that the profit that we made
today is made considering one contract
execution.
>> Yeah.
>> So you need to multiply it for the
amount of margin you have available to
open three, four, five contract.
>> We are out. We are 1,000 in profit for
the day. We are out. Now what we can do
again is if this breaks the high try
the squeeze.
>> Okay.
From here but it needs to break the
high.
>> You need a close again.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Squeeze the from here. Getting
$1,000 profit.
I think we can reach this easily if the
price squeeze correctly. Mhm.
So now we are 1,000 another 1,000 per
contract. Consider that with
five contract available you will close
the day at 10,000.
>> Yeah.
>> People don't consider how much profit it
is. But if you can do this in these
days,
this candle close we are in.
>> Mhm.
>> You can also get a little bit more
aggressive. For example, this one it's
$290 each contract. You can get two
contract and get 600 risk to make other
2,000.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Now we are making all the trades with
one contract. So we just consider one
contract. We need to be with a candle
out of this area.
>> Yeah.
>> For confirming trades.
>> Still no.
Did you ever
in the beginning when when looking at
charts in this way when price got above
just enter without the closure?
>> I that's the reason now I'm so calm.
What would you say helped you to
overcome that?
>> Uh the equity line.
The equity line. You see this one is not
accepting is didn't close. Now this is
the first candle that can close above
>> and we need to adapt. Like if the candle
for example is closing here, it's still
valid but we need to take other $100 of
risk.
>> Okay.
>> So we just need a candle that close. At
the moment is not closing. And every
time that you reject, as I told you, the
setup gets weaker and weaker. So every
time I get more um demanding from my
setup. So for example, now I expect for
a breakout of this.
>> Mhm.
>> So I need a breakout of this level. I
will take still $385
to target for
>> I think what you said is right though in
terms of uh the day the day that we're
trading today with obviously that large
gap that is a large gap as well. 3% um
of a gap that got reclaimed and then we
did have some decent movement after that
reclaim as well in London right um as
well as coming into New York we had a
very good move that we captured as well
so you know in reality
we could have this move but we could
also just chop and chop
>> probably for the way this presenting
like breaking the high of the
consolidation and getting in this chop
It's a decision day and it's Monday.
Yeah,
>> it's really common. Yeah, Monday that it
happens like Monday and Friday are my
worst day in performance.
>> Yeah,
>> because they are not explosion day. They
are I still make profit but the profit
factor is like way lower.
>> Mhm. But um if it breaks there you see
again fake breakout getting back inside
we are just not doing anything just
compressing the only thing that I can
expect is that if we approach this high
we see some acceleration that's the
reason I still say I can also take
double the risk here and risk
$700
if it goes in the worst case scenario
I'm still in profit for the day small
profit but I'm profitable for the day.
>> Yeah. And if you take double the risk,
it's another 2,000 that this will bring
the day to 3,000. Now let's consider we
take this trade and we close the day at
3,000. We are using one contract. Okay,
let's see also to contract is what you
can do with 100,000 $100,000 account.
>> Yeah,
>> it's 3% in one day. People don't
understand how much it is if you can do
this consistently.
>> Of course,
>> like the edge found will be craving for
you like we will be knocking on your
door. It's a good accumulation what he's
doing here. This is a good pattern
taking the low rejecting on the big
trades.
This is really nice.
>> So really when it comes to the the big
buyers and sellers, for example, if a
seller stepped in right now
>> but no follow through, that's great for
that narrative. If a buyer steps in
right now with follow through, that's
great for the narrative.
>> Uh what you don't want to see is a
seller step in and it follows through or
a buyer follow uh fail.
>> Yes. If you are long. Yes. Yeah.
Opposite if you are short like we were
seeing
>> of course
>> see again fake breakouts
>> times
>> with the rules that I created that you
need to see a full body candle above the
eye. You are saving all these small
stops.
>> Yeah.
>> Because you are not engaging. You are
simply not engaging.
I told you NASDAQ is not uncommon that
it will
>> Mhm.
>> do this gain. If it got down there now
though, at this point in the session,
would you still be interested in it or?
>> I would. It would be an amazing trades,
but it means that I need to sacrifice
time with uh with my family and I need
to not eat because I need to manage the
trades. It's really late now for for me.
I will take it, but I will bring it to
break even as soon as possible. And this
is the only set and forget trades that I
will do. And then yeah because this
testing of this I go break even at the
first big volume and then if it reach
the eyes or if u I need to close it uh
before the end of the day I just don't
care.
>> Yeah
>> just I need to be protected as soon as
possible but I need also to protect my
mental health. Yeah, this is something
that people are willing to sacrifice
just to make additional 50 bucks per day
or additional I'm not willing to do it
because I am already in a position where
money it's not important for me and
1,000
plus per day doesn't change my life.
>> Yeah.
>> So I can decide when to engage and where
not to engage. For example, now now we
are doing education but this day I will
say 1,000 it's enough. Tomorrow it's
another day and I will wait for the
explosion day. I was like this is the
goal of every trader. If you can make
money or just close at break even in the
days that your model is not working. So
for example, you have a min reverting
day and you have a trending day, you
close break even a small profit, you're
great.
>> Yeah.
>> Same for trend following model.
>> Whilst we're waiting on this, if we go
down just out of curiosity and I'm sure
there might be some who are might be
thinking this or asking this.
>> 5 minutes or 1 minute?
>> Uh we stay one minute. If we come down
to that level where we rebounded off
>> ah yes this one
>> like there will be people no doubt
thinking
>> like why not why don't we try and
execute there because that's going to
give us such a larger trade right and I
know we talked about it slightly earlier
but like what would your what would your
opinion on that be because um this setup
here is using the opposite logic that
I'm using is using one big run with
lower rate.
>> Yeah. Like I can guarantee to you that
if you watch NASDAQ session opening
seven times out of 10 if you try to get
the aggression you will fail. Three
times out of 10 you will be right and
you will you will take a huge risk to
reward trades.
>> But you have seven red days and three
green days
>> and you don't know when they're
presented.
>> If this is okay for you do it like
volume is greater because it's saying
that these sellers are getting absorbed.
Just I tried this model and it's not for
me. Like when you trade big sides
getting 7 days strict loss that you see
- 10,000 - 5 - 6 it's heavy
>> go to sleep with this heaviness is for
me it's not I I see before I was
searching for the home run you know I
was wanting to take you see it break the
>> Mhm.
>> the session. So this setup of getting
the full candle positioning yourself is
not valid anymore.
This market condition is in reverting.
>> Yeah.
>> So just
going to revisit and this should let
people understand that taking out here
is saving you money.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> Like and if we kept the trade till here,
we didn't only not profit this $250, but
we will also lose $500.
>> So, as you can see, and we can
demonstrate this, risk management is if
not more important at the same level,
>> cuz keep in mind as well that was with
one contract. So, if it was more,
>> if it was more it was 7,500. If it was
10 more, at the end of the month, it
count.
Now the we are completely compressing.
>> Let's see if we accelerate a little bit
to get to this final point.
>> If not and call it a day there because
it's been incredible.
>> If not,
>> we got to see everything though. We got
to see break even. We got to see four
hours of
>> I know. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think we will just close the day
because it's full consolidation rits.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh we'll just check later how it
went. If it closed the low volume node
and went up.
>> Yeah. Yeah, we'll get a screenshot or
something going for sure. Everyone at
home, finally we come to an end. Drop a
comment of your biggest takeaway from
this episode. Did you enjoy the live
trading segment? If so, drop it in the
comments. Let the people know out there
that they need to be doing live trading
here on Chartax as well. Obviously, a
massive shout out to Fabio because it
takes a lot. It wasn't planned. I, you
know, I didn't ask him. He he offered to
do this which is incredible and such
incredible trading skill and you get to
see it here live what a true
professional trader does but also what a
true professional playbook and strategy
looks like really. Um but links for
Fabio will be in the description below
so make sure you check that out right
now. Uh hit subscribe, hit like. Other
episodes are on screen. We've been chaff
and until next time, take